<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/">



<channel rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/listing/RSS">
  <title>Free software jobs</title>
  <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/listing</link>
  <description>This is a meeting place where skilled and informed individuals working in the world of free software come to find job opportunities they can believe in.</description>
  <image rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/logo.png"/>

  <items>
    <rdf:Seq>
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/wordpress-engineer-first-look-media"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/thinkpenguin-gnu-linux-desktop-support-tech"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/the-document-foundation-2013-quality-assurance-engineer"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/sunlight-foundation-software-developer-civic-hacker"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/fsf-seeks-full-time-senior-gnu-linux-systems-administrator-2"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/wikimedia-research-analyst-fundraising"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/data-gov-it-specialist"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/kde-e-v-event-manager"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/creative-commons-web-developer-system-administrator"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/openelections-python-programmer"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/openhumans-org-lead-software-engineer"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/chattanooga-public-library-data-specialist"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/aleph-objects-is-expanding"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/electronic-frontier-foundation-activist"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/the-document-foundation-web-graphics-designer"/>
      
    </rdf:Seq>
  </items>

</channel>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/wordpress-engineer-first-look-media">
    <title>WordPress Engineer - First Look Media</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/wordpress-engineer-first-look-media</link>
    <description>First Look Media is looking for a WordPress Engineer based in either their San Francisco or Manhattan office.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>Founded by Pierre Omidyar, <a href="https://firstlook.org/">First Look Media</a> is based on the belief that democracy depends on a citizenry that is highly informed and deeply engaged in the issues that affect their lives. First Look seeks to improve society through journalism and technology, to help individuals hold the powerful accountable, build responsive institutions and, most important, shape their communities and what happens in their lives for the better.</p>
<h4>POSITION SUMMARY</h4>
<p>First Look Media is looking for a software developer to support FLM's digital magazines. The Wordpress Engineer will provide domain expertise especially around Wordpress themes and the interaction of plugins, CSS, Ajax and Javascript in a multisite Wordpress environment at scale. Participate as a key member of a software development team focused on the implementation and continuous improvement of software development tools and methodologies with a focus on sustainable, professional quality engineering with a team approach. You must be able to thrive in a start-up environment and be able to work both collaboratively and independently as needed. This role can be based in either our San Francisco or Manhattan office.</p>
<h4>Responsibilities:</h4>
<ul>
<li>Collaborate with the Product and Editorial Teams on projects.</li>
<li>Work closely with Designers and Product Teams to develop and launch new themes and sites</li>
<li>Create, edit, and modify themes for a CMS frameworks</li>
<li>Review design changes against analytical data and recommend improvements</li>
<li>Present multiple prototype solutions to high level requirements</li>
<li>Work cross-functionally with software developers and Site Operations personnel</li>
<li>Write tests to support Continuous Integration</li>
</ul>
<h4>Qualifications:</h4>
<ul>
<li>BA/BS degree or equivalent</li>
<li>5+ years as a web or Front-end developer</li>
<li>Experience with n-tier architectures, dynamic content, data caching strategies, and complex security models/implementations</li>
<li>CSS wizard</li>
<li>Experience with responsive design</li>
<li>UI/UX literacy</li>
<li>Expertise with Javascript frameworks</li>
<li>Wordpress Internals Expert including plugins and themes.</li>
<li>Expert with Cross browser support techniques</li>
<li>Strong problem solving skills</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to deliver aggressive project schedules on time</li>
<li>Previous experience configuring and using any or all of the following highly desirable: HTML[5], PHP, AJAX, SOAP, Ant, Subversion, Git, Varnish, HAProxy, Wordpress, chef, puppet</li>
<li>Experience developing and integrating Web services APIs through web services</li>
</ul>
<p>Applicants can apply online at <a href="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/boards.greenhouse.io/firstlook/jobs/20107">boards.greenhouse.io/firstlook/jobs/20107</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-08-06T18:03:38Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/thinkpenguin-gnu-linux-desktop-support-tech">
    <title>ThinkPenguin - GNU/Linux Desktop Support Tech</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/thinkpenguin-gnu-linux-desktop-support-tech</link>
    <description>ThinkPenguin is hiring a GNU/Linux Desktop Support Tech!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.thinkpenguin.com/">ThinkPenguin, Inc</a>, focused on making free software adoption easy and hassle free is looking for an enthusiastic advocate to fill a tier one technical support role. The job is at our offices in Flemington, New Jersey.</p>
<p>The company is focused on expanding the worlds access to free software friendly hardware. In doing so we aim to make it easier for the masses to adopt free software. </p>
<p>Main Responsibilities:</p>
<ul>
<li>assembling (mostly) &amp; repairing computers</li>
<li>packing &amp; shipping orders</li>
<li>diagnose and resolve technical hardware and software issues</li>
<li>providing basic tier one technical support</li>
<li>respond to customer requests for technical assistance in person (occasionally, local area only), via phone, and email (mostly phone/email)</li>
<li>research questions and solutions using internal and external documentation</li>
<li>identify and escalate situations requiring attention</li>
</ul>
<p>Requires:</p>
<ul>
<li>30 hours / week (10:30AM-5:00PM M-F /w half hour lunch break)</li>
<li>vehicle &amp; drivers license</li>
<li>skill in diagnosing problems</li>
<li>good communication skills</li>
<li>attention to detail</li>
<li>patience</li>
<li>a basic understanding of free software and its philosophy</li>
<li>basic GNU/Linux administrations skills/commands (ie: apt-get, md5sum, dmesg, lsusb, lspci, cat, etc)</li>
<li>staying current with the latest GNU/Linux distributions and other free software components / operating systems</li>
<li>Education and Experience:  degree, degree seeking, or related experience and training in troubleshooting and providing help desk support are preferred</li>
</ul>
<p>Key Skills &amp; Competencies</p>
<ul>
<li>oral and written communication skills</li>
<li>customer service oriented</li>
<li>problem analysis</li>
<li>problem-solving</li>
<li>adaptability</li>
<li>planning and organizing</li>
<li>attention to detail</li>
<li>stress tolerance</li>
<li>can work with little to no supervision</li>
</ul>
<p>Email your resume for consideration with salary requirements to <a href="mailto:jobs@thinkpenguin.com">jobs@thinkpenguin.com</a>.</p>
<p>All resumes must be submitted in a free format (such as plain text, PDF, or OpenDocument, and not Microsoft Word). Email submissions that do not follow these instructions will be overlooked.</p>
<p>We are an equal opportunity employer, committed to promoting a diverse workplace, and do not discriminate based on gender, sex, race, color, religion, national origin, age, disability, marital status, or sexual orientation.</p>
<p>Find out more at: <a href="https://www.thinkpenguin.com/gnu-linux/gnulinux-desktop-support-tech">https://www.thinkpenguin.com/gnu-linux/gnulinux-desktop-support-tech</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-06-19T18:45:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/the-document-foundation-2013-quality-assurance-engineer">
    <title>The Document Foundation – Quality Assurance Engineer</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/the-document-foundation-2013-quality-assurance-engineer</link>
    <description>The Document Foundation, the charitable entity behind the world’s leading free office suite LibreOffice, seeks a Quality Assurance Engineer to start work as soon as possible.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.documentfoundation.org/">The Document Foundation (TDF)</a>, the charitable entity behind the world’s leading free office suite <a href="https://www.libreoffice.org/">LibreOffice</a>, seeks a Quality Assurance Engineer to start work as soon as possible.</p>
<p>The role, which is scheduled for twenty hours a week, includes amongst other items:</p>
<ul>
<li>stress testing LibreOffice development builds daily on multiple platforms</li>
<li>help onboarding new QA contributors</li>
<li>help community outreach to encourage more people to join the QA team</li>
<li>confirming bug fixes</li>
<li>triaging unconfirmed bugs on master</li>
<li>running master to try to find regressions early in release cycles</li>
<li>keeping a continuous overview and reporting on the state and progress of LibreOffice QA as seen on its bug trackers, mailing lists, and other communication channels (e.g. IRC)</li>
<li>creating, improving, and keeping up-to-date and understandable documentation, howtos and introductions for volunteers to LibreOffice QA</li>
</ul>
<p>The role requires the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>An established relationship within the quality assurance team as well as with other teams including developers, marketing, and users</li>
<li>Ability to build and run LibreOffice daily on different platforms</li>
<li>Understanding of many of the features within each component and ability to learn other features quickly</li>
<li>Stress testing each component daily</li>
<li>Understanding of <a href="http://www.bugzilla.org/">BugZilla</a></li>
<li>A general understanding of LibreOffice code</li>
<li>Ability to write automated tests to ensure consistent quality in future releases</li>
<li>An understanding of quality assurance procedures</li>
<li>A firm understanding of bibisect – both the code and how to use it</li>
</ul>
<p>Highly proficient in written English, with good spoken English, a working knowledge of other languages appreciated.</p>
<p>The work time during the day is flexible, apart from some fixed times when availability is required (e.g. during meetings, which usually take place at 1500 or 1600 UTC once per week). Applicants are also expected to be available at least two days per week.</p>
<p>TDF welcomes applications from all suitably qualified persons regardless of their race, sex, disability, religion/belief, sexual orientation, or age.</p>
<p>Suitably qualified Members of The Document Foundation (“Board of Trustees”) are preferred over other applicants.</p>
<p>The job is offered on a freelance basis. Work happens from the applicant’s home office, which can be located anywhere in the world.</p>
<p>TDF is looking forward to receiving your applications, including curriculum vitae, your financial expectations, and the earliest date of your availability, via e-mail to Florian Effenberger at <a href="mailto: floeff@documentfoundation.org">floeff@documentfoundation.org</a> no later than May 31st, 2014. You can encrypt your message via OpenPGP/GnuPG.</p>
<p>If you haven’t received feedback by July 31st, 2014, your application could not be considered.</p>
<p>Find out more and apply at: <a href="http://blog.documentfoundation.org/2014/05/01/tdf-freelance-job-opening-201405-01-quality-assurance-engineer/">http://blog.documentfoundation.org/2014/05/01/tdf-freelance-job-opening-201405-01-quality-assurance-engineer/</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-05-12T20:55:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/sunlight-foundation-software-developer-civic-hacker">
    <title>Sunlight Foundation - Software Developer/Civic Hacker!</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/sunlight-foundation-software-developer-civic-hacker</link>
    <description>Sunlight Foundation is hiring a Software Developer/Civic Hacker!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://sunlightfoundation.com/">The Sunlight Foundation</a> is looking for an enthusiastic software developer to join our ranks in Washington, D.C. and expand the breadth and sophistication of our work with government data.</p>
<p>We collect huge amounts of information throughout the day from all over Congress, the U.S. executive branch, and state and municipal governments. We use this information to build powerful, useful websites (such as <a href="http://openstates.org/">Open States</a> and <a href="https://scout.sunlightfoundation.com/">Scout</a>; mobile applications (such as our Congress apps for Android); and APIs (like <a href="https://sunlightfoundation.com/api/">these</a>).</p>
<p>We want to do more of all of this. If you take this position, you'll be asked to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Help us maintain and improve systems that serve millions of people.</li>
<li>Find and incorporate new sources of useful data into our APIs and applications.</li>
<li>Create new free software tools that solve real problems for Sunlight, our users and others in the open government community.</li>
<li>Research and develop cutting edge ways of using our data to create innovative features and solve new kinds of problems.</li>
<li>Notice what we're not doing but should be, and do it.</li>
</ul>
<p>You'll also be asked to use a wide variety of programming languages and technologies.</p>
<p>Some technologies we use at Sunlight:</p>
<ul>
<li>Web, system, and tool development with Ruby, Python, and Node.</li>
<li>Front-end and data visualization in JavaScript (and especially D3).</li>
<li>Both SQL and NoSQL, with PostgreSQL and MongoDB.</li>
<li>Searching lots of text using Elasticsearch and language analysis.</li>
<li>Native app development on Android (Java).</li>
</ul>
<p>You don't need to know all of these, but you should know a couple of them, and be able to learn some others.</p>
<p>Sunlight works in both cyberspace and the physical world, so in addition to writing code, it would be an extra bonus if you enjoy writing about your work, public speaking on Sunlight's behalf or meeting with people both inside and outside of government.</p>
<p>Developers at Sunlight contribute to free software projects, blog posts, policy papers and even enacted legislation. We are looking for people who are excited about using digital tools to make our society better.</p>
<p>This job is based in our Dupont Circle offices in Washington, D.C. You will need to live in the area or be willing to relocate.</p>
<p>To apply, visit the link below and submit a resume, cover letter and your contact information. We ask that applicants remove their name and other personal information from their resume and cover letter so that our candidate screening process can be conducted impartially. More details are available on the form submission page.</p>
<p>We will use email to confirm receipt of all applications. No phone calls, please.</p>
<p>Find out more and apply at : <a href="http://sunlightfoundation.com/jobs/190/">http://sunlightfoundation.com/jobs/190/</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-05-09T20:35:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/fsf-seeks-full-time-senior-gnu-linux-systems-administrator-2">
    <title>FSF seeks full-time senior GNU/Linux systems administrator</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/fsf-seeks-full-time-senior-gnu-linux-systems-administrator-2</link>
    <description>FSF seeks full-time senior GNU/Linux systems administrator</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.fsf.org/">Free Software Foundation (FSF)</a>, a Boston-based 501(c)(3) charity with a worldwide mission to protect freedoms critical to the computer-using public, seeks a full-time senior systems administrator.</p>
<p>The ideal candidate will be a well-rounded GNU/Linux systems administrator who thrives on constant broad-based learning and problem-solving. (S)he will be familiar with the free software community and how it works, and will be more interested in making a substantial contribution to software freedom and having employment consistent with ethical ideals than obtaining the highest salary.</p>
<p>This is an opportunity to work for the organization that started the <a href="http://www.gnu.org/gnu/thegnuproject.html">GNU Project</a>, launched the free software movement, and safeguards the <a href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html">GNU General Public License</a>. The position includes frequent contact and collaboration with many of the core GNU developers, and currently reports to the executive director.</p>
<p>Together, the senior systems administrators have a great deal of influence over technology decisions within the FSF, and do crucial work empowering thousands of others to develop free software.</p>
<p>With our small staff of twelve, each person makes a clear contribution. We work hard, but offer a humane and fun work environment.</p>
<p>The FSF is a mature and growing organization that provides great potential for advancement; existing staff are prioritized for any new job openings.</p>
<h3>Example systems administration tasks include:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Be a lead voice in the Foundation's software system decision-making</li>
<li>Install and maintain fully free GNU/Linux systems on servers,
    desktops, laptops, and embedded devices</li>
<li>Support GNU developers and FSF staff in their use of FSF-owned systems</li>
<li>Monitor and improve system security and network infrastructure</li>
<li>Spec and purchase new equipment</li>
<li>Coordinate work of volunteer systems administrators</li>
<li>Share in the on-call rotation to deal with core system emergencies</li>
<li>Learn about and work with cutting-edge free technologies like <a href="http://www.coreboot.org/Welcome_to_coreboot">Coreboot</a></li>
<li>Blog publicly about the technologies and techniques used at the FSF; inform FSF policy positions in technical areas</li>
</ul>
<h3>Programming is occasionally required, such as:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Fix bugs and submit patches upstream for the software used at the FSF</li>
<li>Design, write, and release new software when existing software doesn't fit the bill</li>
<li>Improve and maintain existing custom software</li>
</ul>
<h3>Useful specific experience includes:</h3>
<ul>
<li>4+ years experience as a GNU/Linux systems administrator</li>
<li>3+ years experience with at least two programming languages</li>
<li>2+ years experience with an apt-based GNU/Linux distribution</li>
<li>1+ years experience with SQL (preferably PostgreSQL or MySQL)</li>
<li>Undergraduate college degree, or in lieu of degree, substantially more experience than that listed above</li>
<li>A portfolio of contributions to free software projects or their development infrastructure</li>
</ul>
<h3>Expected technical skills are:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Expert knowledge of systems administration for GNU/Linux with apt-based distributions</li>
<li>In-depth understanding of key network protocols such as TCP/IP,
    BGP, DNS, SMTP, HTTP, FTP, NFS, DHCP, etc.</li>
<li>In-depth understanding of key system components such as
    virtualization, automated systems management, software RAID, MTAs,
    etc.</li>
<li>In-depth knowledge of Drupal and Nginx.</li>
<li>Familiarity with at least two of Perl, PHP, Python or Ruby. High
    proficiency (expert preferred) in at least one of these languages</li>
<li>Thorough knowledge of network and system security, especially as
    related to the kernel Linux and common Internet services</li>
<li>Knowledge of network routing and related services in GNU/Linux,
    such as iptables and stateful firewalls.</li>
<li>Ability to design SQL databases</li>
<li>Ability to spec, purchase, assemble, and debug components for
    custom-build server systems</li>
</ul>
<h3>We will prefer candidates with additional skills, such as:</h3>
<ul>
<li>In-depth knowledge of CiviCRM, Xen, Puppet, Exim, Spamassassin,
    Mailman, Quagga, Apache, RT, Coreboot, Squid, Zope, Plone,
    Semantic Mediawiki, CAS, Django, SQL Ledger</li>
<li>Knowledge of version control systems: Git, Subversion, CVS, RCS</li>
<li>Soldering, making your own Ethernet cable, extremely high Nethack scores</li>
</ul>
<h3>We also require:</h3>
<ul>
<li>A willingness to learn and understand how political and
    philosophical positions of an organization impact computing
    requirements</li>
<li>An ability to work as part of a team and to handle and coordinate
    contributions from a volunteer core</li>
<li>Being open-minded and tolerant of others</li>
</ul>
<h2>Benefits and salary</h2>
<p>The job must be worked on-site at FSF's downtown Boston offices, because it involves caring for equipment that is physically located there.</p>
<p>It is a union position. The salary is fixed at $61,651 and is non-negotiable. Other benefits include:</p>
<ul>
<li>reimbursement for some relocation expenses,</li>
<li>full family health coverage through Blue Cross/Blue Shield's HMO Blue program,</li>
<li>subsidized dental plan,</li>
<li>four weeks of paid vacation annually,</li>
<li>seventeen paid holidays annually,</li>
<li>public transit commuting cost reimbursement,</li>
<li>403(b) program through TIAA-CREF,</li>
<li>yearly cost-of-living pay increases, and</li>
<li>potential for an annual performance bonus.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Application instructions</h2>
<p>The position is available immediately, and we will be accepting
applications until it is filled. </p>
<p>Applications must be submitted via email to <a href="mailto:hiring@fsf.org">&#104;&#105;&#114;&#105;&#110;&#103;&#64;&#102;&#115;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a>. The
email must contain the subject line, "Senior Systems Administrator." A
complete application should include:</p>
<ul>
<li>cover letter,</li>
<li>resume,</li>
<li>contact information for three references, and</li>
<li>links to any published free software work.</li>
</ul>
<p>All materials must be in a free format (such as plain text, PDF, or OpenDocument, and <strong>not</strong> Microsoft Word). Email submissions that do not
follow these instructions will be overlooked. No phone calls, please.</p>
<p>An on-site interview will be required with the executive director and the technology team.</p>
<p>We are an equal opportunity employer, committed to promoting a diverse workplace, and do not discriminate based on gender, sex, race, color, religion, national origin, age, disability, marital status, or sexual
orientation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-05-06T20:55:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/wikimedia-research-analyst-fundraising">
    <title>Wikimedia - Research Analyst - Fundraising</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/wikimedia-research-analyst-fundraising</link>
    <description>Wikimedia Foundation is hiring a Research Analyst!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Analytics">The Analytics</a> team in the <a href="http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Home">Wikimedia Foundation</a> is looking for a full-time research analyst -
fundraising. You can read more about the position <a href="http://hire.jobvite.com/CompanyJobs/Careers.aspx?c=qSa9VfwQ&amp;cs=9UL9Vfwt&amp;page=Job%20Description&amp;j=o2AJYfw3">here</a>.
Please submit your job application using <a href="http://hire.jobvite.com/CompanyJobs/Careers.aspx?c=qSa9VfwQ&amp;cs=9UL9Vfwt&amp;page=Apply&amp;j=o2AJYfw3">this link</a>.</p>
<h2>Job Description</h2>
<p>The Wikimedia Foundation -- the non-profit organization that operates <a href="https://www.wikipedia.org/">Wikipedia</a> and its sister projects -- runs every year a global fundraising campaign to support its projects. Every year, millions of donors donate an average $15 each to keep our projects running. The Fundraising team is
looking for a researcher to take the lead on its research and experimentation strategy, to make Wikipedia's fundraising campaigns faster, better and stronger and to stay true to our values of openness, transparency and respect of user privacy.</p>
<p>You will work on a daily basis with designers, software engineers and product owners in the Fundraising team for designing and testing new strategies to make Wikimedia projects financially sustainable. You will also be a full member of the Wikimedia Foundation's Research &amp; Data team - a team of researchers responsible for building a comprehensive body of knowledge about Wikipedia contributors and readers, designing novel methods and analytics tools and helping the Foundation design and evaluate high-impact products.</p>
<p>You are an excellent communicator and a mission-driven researcher, you enjoy replacing anecdotes with cold, hard data and using quantitative methods to answer complex questions, and you feel strongly about Wikimedia's mission to provide the sum of all human knowledge for free to every person on the planet.</p>
<h2>Responsibilities</h2>
<ul>
<li>Lead the fundraising research agenda in coordination with the team and help turn ideas into testable hypotheses. Design tests and online experiments to measure the effectiveness of a range of fundraising strategies and understand donor behavior.</li>
<li>Drive the entire fundraiser research pipeline from exploratory analysis and test design, to data analysis and statistical modeling, writing and presenting results. Assure the quality of data and the robustness of the results.</li>
<li>Collaborate closely with fundraising operations and engineers to ensure that tooling and monitoring tools and systems are working accurately during fundraisers.</li>
<li>Work with analytics engineers on the design of tools to present and visualize the results of your work and better support decision-makers.</li>
<li>Actively contribute to the activities of the Research and Data team, collaborate on other research projects and help spearhead a data-intensive culture in the organization. Share and communicate the results of your work within the team, the organization, the volunteer and the research community</li>
</ul>
<h2>Requirements</h2>
<ul>
<li>PhD or Master's degree in computer science, statistics, mathematics, operations research, behavioral science, economics, or a related quantitative field (or the equivalent combination of education and experience) and 5 years of relevant work or research experience</li>
<li>A record of experience in at least three of the following areas: experimental design and multivariate testing; statistical modeling, time series and regression analysis; large-scale data mining; human-computer interaction; analysis of (online) donor behavior, online advertising or monetization.</li>
<li>Fluency with scientific computing tools and programming languages for data analysis required. Experience with R and python is a big plus.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Set yourself apart</h2>
<p>In addition to the basic skills needed for being successful these skills could set you apart.</p>
<ul>
<li>A record of relevant research publications or a portfolio of relevant free software projects you significantly contributed to. Links to public projects, blogs, etc. are exceptionally useful</li>
<li>Experience with large-scale, unstructured data streams; fluency in Pig, Hive and familiarity with Hadoop a plus.</li>
<li>Familiarity with free software communities.</li>
<li>Experience editing Wikipedia or its sister projects.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-04-10T20:20:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/data-gov-it-specialist">
    <title>Data.gov - IT specialist</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/data-gov-it-specialist</link>
    <description>Data.gov is looking for an IT Specialist to join their team!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The Information Technology Specialist (INET) position is primarily concerned with the development of technical solutions, business processes, and information technology policies to ensure the functionality of <a href="https://www.data.gov/">Data.gov</a> as the central government-wide website for federal agency free data.  Responsibilities include overseeing technical development and implementation of free data solutions, coordination with federal agencies on free data issues, and conducting outreach to federal agencies, citizens, and other stakeholders republishing free data from across the federal government of Data.gov.</p>
<p>This position is located in the Office of Citizens Services and Innovative Technologies (OCSIT), Office of Innovative Technologies (OIT), General Services Administration (GSA) in Washington DC.<br />
</p>
<h4>GSA offers its employees a wide range of benefits including:</h4>
<ul>
<li>Federal health insurance plans (choose from a wide range of plans)</li>
<li>Life insurance coverage with several options to choose from</li>
<li>Leave policies to help you take care of your personal, recreational, and health care needs</li>
<li>Thrift Savings Plan (similar to a 401(k) plan)</li>
<li>Flexible work schedules and telework</li>
<li>Transit and child care subsidies</li>
<li>Training and development</li>
</ul>
<p>Apply as Merit Promotion (open to current federal employees): <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov/GetJob/ViewDetails/363325400">https://www.usajobs.gov/GetJob/ViewDetails/363325400</a></p>
<p>Apply as Delegated Examining (open to all sources): <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov/GetJob/ViewDetails/363324500">https://www.usajobs.gov/GetJob/ViewDetails/363324500</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-03-10T19:55:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/kde-e-v-event-manager">
    <title>KDE e.V. - Event Manager</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/kde-e-v-event-manager</link>
    <description>KDE e.V. is looking for an Event Manager!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ev.kde.org/">KDE e.V.</a> is looking for an event manager to lead the organisation of its annual event <a href="http://akademy2013.kde.org/">Akademy</a>, where a charming community of free software enthusiasts meets to change the world.</p>
<p>This is a limited contract starting immediately and is expected to end in November 2014. The exact timing and duration of the contract will be agreed upon with the applicant. The position can be based in KDE e.V.'s office in Berlin, but the position is also open to remote work. The event manager is expected to attend the conference and provide on-the-ground management and logistics during the event.</p>
<h2>Responsibilities</h2>
<ul>
<li>Drive the organisation of KDE's annual community gathering in collaboration with the local team and other volunteers</li>
<li>Support the community in defining the content of the event</li>
<li>Coordinate volunteers</li>
<li>Negotiate with and support sponsors and partners</li>
<li>Negotiate and coordinate with vendors</li>
<li>Assist some of the participants with travel arrangements</li>
<li>Support the community in reporting about the event</li>
</ul>
<h2>Qualification</h2>
<ul>
<li>Experience with organising large events</li>
<li>Fluent in English (spoken and written). German is a plus. Czech is a plus.</li>
<li>Experience working in the open and in a volunteer community</li>
<li>Self-organized and motivated hands-on personality</li>
</ul>
<h2>What KDE has to offer</h2>
<ul>
<li>Working with a highly motivated team of volunteers</li>
<li>Collaborating with people from all around the world</li>
<li>Chance to make a difference for a large free software community</li>
</ul>
<h2>How to Apply</h2>
<p>Please send your application by email to <a href="mailto:kde-ev-board@kde.org">&#107;&#100;&#101;&#45;&#101;&#118;&#45;&#98;&#111;&#97;&#114;&#100;&#64;&#107;&#100;&#101;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a> (subject: event manager application). Please also don't hesitate to contact us if you have any questions.</p>
<h2>About KDE e.V.</h2>
<p><a href="http://ev.kde.org/">KDE e.V.</a> is a non-profit organization dedicated to representing the <a href="http://www.kde.org/">KDE project</a> in legal and financial issues. The KDE Community is an international technology team dedicated to creating a free and user-friendly computing experience, offering an advanced graphical desktop, a wide variety of applications for communication, work, education and entertainment and a platform to easily build new applications upon. </p>
<p>More information about the job posting can be found here: <a href="http://ev.kde.org/resources/eventmanager-advert.pdf">http://ev.kde.org/resources/eventmanager-advert.pdf</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-03-07T17:35:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/creative-commons-web-developer-system-administrator">
    <title>[CLOSED] Creative Commons - Web Developer/System Administrator</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/creative-commons-web-developer-system-administrator</link>
    <description>Creative Commons is hiring a Web Developer/ Systems Administrator!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creativecommons.org/">Creative Commons</a> is looking for a full time Web Developer/Systems Administrator to develop and maintain the sites and systems that power CC on the Web.</p>
<p>This is a unique role which requires a focus on building scalable, rock-solid architecture to power our high-traffic websites, as well as an ability to move higher in the stack to implement new features or develop new websites and services.</p>
<p>Creative Commons has an office in Mountain View, CA and some staff that live in other states and countries. This position is open both to candidates located in Mountain View and candidates living within four hours of the US/Canada Pacific time zone (UTC -8).</p>
<p>This role works closely with the rest of the Creative Commons staff to support their IT needs, and must be able to prioritize tasks and requirements coming from different stakeholders including Creative Commons affiliates and community members who depend on or help maintain the sites.</p>
<h2>Essential duties and responsibilities:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Maintenance of core server infrastructure, both physical and virtual</li>
<li>Development, testing, and documentation of websites and web services</li>
<li>Support, tuning, maintenance, and documentation of our operating processes including builds, code deployment, patch management, and troubleshooting of issues</li>
<li>Monitoring services and writing automation tools to enable robust, scalable services</li>
<li>Handle problems from communication to implementing solutions, to post-mortems and process changes to prevent recurrence</li>
<li>Help coordinate on-site and remote desktop support occasionally, as needed</li>
</ul>
<h2>Skill Requirements</h2>
<ul>
<li>Demonstrated proficiency in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and PHP</li>
<li>Comfortable with GLAMP stack, and common GLAMP apps (WordPress, <a href="http://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/MediaWiki">MediaWiki</a>, etc)</li>
<li>Experience &amp; passion supporting a production infrastructure</li>
<li>Solid scripting knowledge (Python, Ruby, Perl, shell)</li>
<li>Passion to automate and document everything</li>
<li>Ability to troubleshoot complex issues</li>
<li>Knowledge of network services and protocols (SMTP, DNS, LDAP, etc)</li>
</ul>
<h2>Preferred Skills</h2>
<ul>
<li>Config management and orchestration experience (Puppet, Chef, CFEngine, etc.)</li>
<li>Experience deploying and optimizing services on AWS</li>
<li>Track record of participation in free software communities</li>
<li>Bachelor’s degree in Computer Science (but real-world experience is preferred)</li>
</ul>
<h2>Work Environment</h2>
<ul>
<li>Collaborative, community-building atmosphere</li>
<li>Office is an open pod setting in downtown Mountain View, walking distance to a myriad of restaurants, and easily accessible via car and public transportation</li>
<li>We have a shared kitchen, catered lunches a few times per month, and host a monthly happy hour for staff and guests</li>
<li>CC provides everything you need to do your best work which includes ergonomically sound equipment and a flexible work schedule</li>
<li>Travel required (including international)</li>
</ul>
<h2>How to Apply</h2>
<p>Please email your cover letter and resume to <a href="mailto:jobs@creativecommons.org">&#106;&#111;&#98;&#115;&#64;&#99;&#114;&#101;&#97;&#116;&#105;&#118;&#101;&#99;&#111;&#109;&#109;&#111;&#110;&#115;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a> with the subject heading of “Web Developer/Systems Administrator Application.”</p>
<p>Find out more at: <a href="https://creativecommons.org/opportunities#webdevsysadmin">https://creativecommons.org/opportunities#webdevsysadmin</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-01-31T23:40:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/openelections-python-programmer">
    <title>OpenElections - Python Programmer</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/openelections-python-programmer</link>
    <description>OpenElections is looking for a part-time Python programmer!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://blog.openelections.net/">OpenElections Project</a> is looking for a part-time Python
programmer to help our Knight-funded effort to liberate election
data from across the country. The role involves:</p>
<ul>
<li>Writing code to obtain, transform, and output election results data in different formats.</li>
<li>Helping volunteer coders integrate their work into our data processing system.</li>
<li>Work with the core team to extend/refine the data processing system.</li>
<li>Help build a website to provide easy access to data for the public.</li>
</ul>
<p>The ideal candidate will have solid Python programming chops,
experience with <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/">MongoDB</a>, and an interest in free
data. Front-end coding skills are a bonus. This is a part-time,
contract position with a target of 15-20 hours per week. Hourly
fee is commensurate with experience.</p>
<p>If interested, please contact Sara Schnadt at <a href="mailto:sschnadt.projects@gmail.com">&#115;&#115;&#99;&#104;&#110;&#97;&#100;&#116;&#46;&#112;&#114;&#111;&#106;&#101;&#99;&#116;&#115;&#64;&#103;&#109;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#109;</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-01-29T20:20:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/openhumans-org-lead-software-engineer">
    <title>Openhumans.org - Lead Software Engineer</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/openhumans-org-lead-software-engineer</link>
    <description>Openhumans.org  is hiring a Lead Software Engineer!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>As the Lead Software Engineer at <personalgenomes.org> you will work on the <a href="http://openhumans.org">Open Humans Network</a>, a project that aims to help people aggregate and share their health and trait data to advance scientific, educational and humanitarian causes.</p>
<p>Our model for this initiative is the work we’ve done on the <a href="http://www.personalgenomes.org/">Harvard Personal Genome Project (PGP)</a>, which has over 3,000 volunteers publicly sharing extensive biological and trait data, including hundreds of whole genomes, exomes, and genotyping data sets, over 1,000 health records, microbiome datasets from various bodily habitats, device data, brain imaging, etc. This combination of a highly informed and engaged community of volunteers and their contributions of extremely rich biological and health data, along with a network of collaboration-minded researchers, is an incredibly powerful scientific and educational resource that is unrivaled elsewhere. We will build on this momentum with this exciting new initiative that will transform participatory research and advance human health.</p>
<h3>We're looking for someone who...</h3>
<ul>
<li>Is interested in building and managing a full-stack website. As the Lead Software Engineer, you’ll be able to make decisions about what kind of technology is used and how it’s deployed.</li>
<li>Has used multiple programming languages to build production systems (e.g. Python, Ruby).</li>
<li>Is experienced with back-end web development (e.g. Rails or Django).</li>
<li>Is comfortable managing Unix-like servers and has opinions about how to store and disseminate large datasets (currently around 50TB total, although we would start with managing &lt;10GB).</li>
<li>Works well in a small team of developers and scientists.</li>
<li>Loves science, participatory research, and free software ideals.</li>
<li>Believes in our mission!</li>
</ul>
<h3>About PersonalGenomes.org</h3>
<p>PersonalGenomes.org (PG.org) is a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization working to generate, aggregate and interpret human biological and trait data on an unprecedented scale. PG.org's mission is to make a wide spectrum of data about humans accessible to increase biological literacy and improve human health. Its efforts are informed by values encouraging greater transparency and collaboration between researchers and participants. PG.org supports the Personal Genome Project (PGP) global network. The first PGP research study was founded at Harvard Medical School in 2005, and PGP sites now exist at leading institutions in four countries. We also produce the annual <a href="http://www.getconference.org/">Genomes, Environments and Traits (GET) Conference</a>. More information is available at <a href="http://www.personalgenomes.org">http://www.personalgenomes.org</a></p>
<h3>About Open Humans</h3>
<p>We have years of practical experience, thousands of participants, and diverse data sets accrued. What we need now is an experienced developer to build a site for participants and researchers to manage and publicly share this data.</p>
<h3>Location</h3>
<p>We would prefer for the software engineer to be based in the Northeast of the United States, ideally Boston or New York City areas. We can be flexible on geography, with the right person. We collaborate with people all over the globe.</p>
<h3>Your experience</h3>
<p>In addition to your resume or CV, please feel free to share any free software projects, side projects, and development experiences you are proud of.</p>
<h3>Compensation</h3>
<p>We offer a competitive salary, commensurate with experience.</p>
<h3>Contact</h3>
<p>Jason Bobe, Executive Director</p>
<p>email: <a href="mailto:jason@personalgenomes.org">&#106;&#97;&#115;&#111;&#110;&#64;&#112;&#101;&#114;&#115;&#111;&#110;&#97;&#108;&#103;&#101;&#110;&#111;&#109;&#101;&#115;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a></p>
<p><a href="http://openhumans.org/#now_hiring">http://openhumans.org/#now_hiring</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-01-22T20:25:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/chattanooga-public-library-data-specialist">
    <title>Chattanooga Public Library - Data Specialist</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/chattanooga-public-library-data-specialist</link>
    <description>Chattanooge Public Library is hiring a data specialist!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://chattlibrary.org">Chattanooga Public Library (CPL)</a> is seeking a qualified candidate for a newly created Data Specialist position. The successful applicant will join our fantastic digital projects team on The 4th Floor, a 14,000 sq ft public maker/hackerspace in Chattanooga’s city center. This is a unique library job that combines the diverse talents of a seasoned collection development specialist, a web developer, a data scientist, and a community outreach specialist. The position is a year-long grant funded position awarded to the CPL as one partner in the <a href="http://openchattanooga.com/">Chattanooga collaborative</a> collaborative. With demonstrated success, we intend to extend the position beyond the duration of the grant indefinitely.</p>
<p>The ideal candidate for the position is a free software evangelist and an expert who can work with representatives from city government as well as citizen groups like <a href="http://openchattanooga.com/">Chattanooga collaborative</a> to coordinate contributions of data to a public platform or portal. This portal will be hosted by the library and accessed alongside our other digital collections. The portal’s exceptional construction, performance, and maintenance are all the responsibility of the DS. The DS will coordinate with partners to ensure that all data added to the portal is useful, useable, and accessible like all of our other public library collections. While this position does not require the candidate to be a degreed librarian, it is important that the candidate demonstrates an understanding of professional collection development principles, since this government-produced data will be treated as a library collection.<br />
</p>
<p>The first and most important task the DS faces is the buildout of the platform itself, as well as the creation of a sustainability plan and documentation of the data portal as a library collection. Currently, the library has a beta version of a data portal available at <a href="http://opendata.chattlibrary.org">http://opendata.chattlibrary.org</a>; this was created using <a href="https://drupal.org/project/dkan">DKAN</a>. The DS will either continue work using this platform, or will present a case for the adoption of another free software platform, such as <a href="http://ckan.org/">CKAN</a>.</p>
<p>Chattanooga Public Library considers this data portal a key piece of our digital infrastructure as we develop more online library services and migrate some of our traditional library services into a networked environment. The ideal candidate will bring innovative and creative thought and workflows to our already robust digital services team. Eventually, the CPL anticipates serving more than just government data transparency from this platform. A candidate with a passion for developing cutting edge services, skills to build and deliver applications and products, and a desire to have fun working collaboratively with the rest of us will find CPL to be a satisfying work environment.</p>
<p>Other qualifications, requirements, and preferences:</p>
<ul>
<li>Undergraduate degree or equivalent experience in CS or related field </li>
<li>Demonstrated understanding of data structures and APIs</li>
<li>Familiarity with Drupal and DKAN or with CKAN</li>
<li>Familiarity with the GLAMP stack; demonstrated PHP development experience</li>
<li>A strong history of contributions and commitments to free software projects</li>
<li>Please provide a link to your <a href="https://github.com/">github</a> account or another online portfolio</li>
<li>Bonus points for applicants with UI/UX/design experience </li>
</ul>
<p>This is a full-time position with benefits. Sorry, this is not a remote work opportunity, you will have to work in the library. </p>
<p>The salary for this job is $55,000/year.</p>
<p>Email application, resume, and portfolio to <a href="mailto:cooper_j@lib.chattanooga.gov">&#99;&#111;&#111;&#112;&#101;&#114;&#95;&#106;&#64;&#108;&#105;&#98;&#46;&#99;&#104;&#97;&#116;&#116;&#97;&#110;&#111;&#111;&#103;&#97;&#46;&#103;&#111;&#118;</a></p>
<p>More information at <a href="http://chattlibrary.org/jobs/open-data-specialist-ods">http://chattlibrary.org/jobs/open-data-specialist-ods</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-01-17T22:35:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/aleph-objects-is-expanding">
    <title>Aleph Objects is expanding!</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/aleph-objects-is-expanding</link>
    <description>Aleph Objects is hiring multiple positions.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<h3>About Aleph Objects</h3>
<p>Frustrated by the status quo, <a href="http://www.alephobjects.com">Aleph Objects, Inc.</a> began with the goal to allow people the freedom they need to get the job done -- specifically, the job of conceiving, creating, and manufacturing prototypes and projects. Built upon the philosophy of freedom, Aleph Objects, Inc., the parent company of <a href="https://www.lulzbot.com/">LulzBot</a> and based in Loveland, Colorado, develops and manufactures a line of libre desktop 3D printers. </p>
<p>Open positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>3D Printer Fleet Technician</li>
<li>Assembler</li>
<li>Chief Financial Officer</li>
<li>Customer Support Representative</li>
<li>Electrical Engineer</li>
<li>Process Engineer/Manager - Injection Molding</li>
<li>Production/Material Planner</li>
<li>Purchasing / Supply Chain Manager</li>
<li>Sales Associate</li>
<li>Shipping / Receiving and Inventory Manager</li>
</ul>
<p>View more detailed information about the jobs here: <a href="http://www.alephobjects.com/jobs.html">http://www.alephobjects.com/jobs.html</a></p>
<p>Aleph Obects, Inc. is committed to creating a diverse environment and is proud to be an equal opportunity employer. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, color, religion, gender, gender identity or expression, sexual orientation, national origin, genetics, disability, age, or veteran status.</p>
<p>Email a resume, in PDF format, to <a href="mailto:jobs@alephobjects.com">&#106;&#111;&#98;&#115;&#64;&#97;&#108;&#101;&#112;&#104;&#111;&#98;&#106;&#101;&#99;&#116;&#115;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#109;</a> with the open position title in the subject heading.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2013-12-06T21:01:33Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/electronic-frontier-foundation-activist">
    <title>Electronic Frontier Foundation - Activist</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/electronic-frontier-foundation-activist</link>
    <description>EFF is Hiring an Activist!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.eff.org">The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF)</a>, a nonprofit organization based in San Francisco, is looking for a full-time activist to fight for free speech, innovation and privacy on the Internet and other technologies. If you are passionate about technology, dedicated to its role in building a better future and want to work alongside leaders in the field, this dream job is for you! As an EFF activist, your responsibilities would include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Communicating our sometimes complex technical and legal issues to "mom and pop" in a clear, compelling, and concise voice;</li>
<li>Developing energetic and innovative education and activism campaigns that engage both EFF's membership and the general public;</li>
<li>Writing blog posts about EFF’s work in a timely manner;</li>
<li>Maintaining the content of EFF's information-packed website;</li>
<li>Working closely with EFF attorneys, technologists, and other public interest groups; and</li>
<li>Determining when issues deserve EFF attention and convincing others of their importance.</li>
</ul>
<p>Required:</p>
<ul>
<li>Excellent writing skills;</li>
<li>Strong familiarity with and passion for digital civil liberties issues;</li>
<li>An eagerness to learn about new issues; and</li>
<li>An ability to turn things around quickly and comprehensively.</li>
</ul>
<p>In addition, knowledge of or experience with any of the following would be advantageous:</p>
<ul>
<li>Collaborative writing and editing;</li>
<li>Professional journalism, or formal training in journalistic or creative writing;</li>
<li>Organizing online activism for an advocacy-oriented nonprofit organization;</li>
<li>Technical skills, including content management systems;</li>
<li>International policy issues; and</li>
<li>Design and/or illustration, especially rendering complex data sets through informational graphics or charts; and</li>
<li>Experience in audio or video production.</li>
</ul>
<p>This is a full-time position based in EFF's office in San Francisco, CA. To apply, send a cover letter with links to 2-4 online writing samples and resume to <a href="mailto:careers@eff.org">&#99;&#97;&#114;&#101;&#101;&#114;&#115;&#64;&#101;&#102;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a>. Feel free to include links to additional supporting materials, as well. We will begin reviewing resumes on December 10th. No phone calls please!</p>
<p>For more information: <a href="https://www.eff.org/opportunities/jobs/activist">https://www.eff.org/opportunities/jobs/activist</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2013-12-04T22:22:18Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/the-document-foundation-web-graphics-designer">
    <title>The Document Foundation - Web Graphics Designer</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/resources/jobs/the-document-foundation-web-graphics-designer</link>
    <description>The Document Foundation is hiring a Web Graphics Designer!</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.documentfoundation.org/">The Document Foundation (TDF)</a>, the charitable entity behind the world’s leading free office suite <a href="https://www.libreoffice.org">LibreOffice</a>, seeks a web graphics designer to start work as soon as possible.</p>
<p>TDF is currently working on completely revamping and redesigning its <a href="https://www.libreoffice.org">LibreOffice website</a>. To support our team, that is working on content, structure and text, someone with graphical skills as well as HTML and CSS knowledge is required. The role, which is scheduled for approximately two to three months part-time, with approximately 20 hours per week, includes amongst other items:</p>
<ul>
<li>graphically designing the CMS template for the website</li>
<li>creation of banners, buttons and graphics to be used in the website, as well as in printed materials</li>
<li>creation of images with vector-based (SVG) as well as bitmap-based (PNG, JPG) formats</li>
<li>editing and updating of existing images, graphics and design</li>
<li>incorporating, and where required adapting, TDF’s design and style guides (CI)</li>
<li>documentation of styles, designs and images created during the project</li>
</ul>
<p>Previous experience with such tasks is highly welcome, so is using free software for creation of the graphics. Speaking and writing English fluently is a mandatory requirement.</p>
<p>The work time during the day is flexible, apart from some fixed times when availability is required to coordinate with the team, which is mostly based in Europe (UTC+1 timezone). Applicants are expected, however, to be available at least three days per week.</p>
<p>Created works are expected to be released under the <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 License</a>, while a copyright transfer to TDF is not required.</p>
<p>The job offered is a project-based one-off, with no immediate plans to a mid- or long-term work relationship.</p>
<p>TDF welcomes applications from all suitably qualified persons regardless of their race, sex, disability, religion/belief, sexual orientation, or age.</p>
<p>Suitably qualified Members of The Document Foundation (“Board of Trustees”) are preferred over other applicants.</p>
<p>The job is offered on a freelance basis. Work happens from the applicant’s home office, which can be located anywhere in the world.</p>
<p>TDF is looking forward to receiving your applications, including curriculum vitae, your financial expectations (name your hourly rate), and the earliest date of your availability, via e-mail to Florian Effenberger at <a href="mailto:floeff@documentfoundation.org">&#102;&#108;&#111;&#101;&#102;&#102;&#64;&#100;&#111;&#99;&#117;&#109;&#101;&#110;&#116;&#102;&#111;&#117;&#110;&#100;&#97;&#116;&#105;&#111;&#110;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a> no later than November 30th, 2013. You can encrypt your message via PGP/GnuPG.</p>
<p>If you haven’t received feedback by December 31st, 2013, your application could not be considered.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.documentfoundation.org/2013/11/05/tdf-freelance-job-opening-201311-02-web-graphics-designer/">http://blog.documentfoundation.org/2013/11/05/tdf-freelance-job-opening-201311-02-web-graphics-designer/</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2013-11-15T19:40:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>Document</dc:type>
  </item>



</rdf:RDF>
