<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/">



<channel rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/aggregator/RSS">
  <title>FSF News</title>
  <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/aggregator</link>
  <description>Latest news from the Free Software Foundation</description>
  <image rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/logo.png"/>

  <items>
    <rdf:Seq>
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-statement-on-alice-corp-v-cls-bank"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/reset-the-net"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/tehnoetic-wireless-usb-adapter-now-fsf-certified-to-respect-your-freedom"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-condemns-partnership-between-mozilla-and-adobe-to-support-digital-restrictions-management"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/global-community-rallies-for-international-day-against-drm"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-seeks-full-time-senior-gnu-linux-systems-administrator-1"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-foundation-statement-on-heartbleed-vulnerability"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-award-winners-announced"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-joins-forces-with-software-freedom-law-center-and-open-source-initiative-to-fight-software-patents-in-u-s-supreme-court"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-foundation-opens-registration-for-march-24th-legal-seminar-on-gpl-enforcement-and-legal-ethics"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/lulzbot-taz-3-3d-printer-now-fsf-certified-to-respect-your-freedom"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/anti-fast-track-mobilization-to-be-extended-after-more-than-half-a-million-people-take-action"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/gift-giving-gnu-advises-shoppers-to-give-freely"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/gluglug-x60-laptop-now-certified-to-respect-your-freedom"/>
      
      
        <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.fsf.org/news/reform-corporate-surveillance"/>
      
    </rdf:Seq>
  </items>

</channel>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-statement-on-alice-corp-v-cls-bank">
    <title>US Supreme Court makes the right decision to nix Alice Corp. patent, but more work needed to end software patents for good</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-statement-on-alice-corp-v-cls-bank</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA -- Thursday, June 19, 2014 -- Today the
United States Supreme Court unanimously ruled a prominent software
patent invalid in the case of Alice Corp. v. CLS Bank, saying that
implementing an abstract idea on a computer does not make that idea
patent-eligible.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The FSF, Software Freedom Law Center (SFLC), and Open
Source Initiative (OSI) had co-filed an <a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2014/alice_v_cls-sflc_amicus.pdf">amicus curiae</a> brief in
the case, stating their position that software on general-purpose
computers is not patentable.</p>
<p>"Today's ruling is an important and meaningful step in the right
direction, but the Court and Congress must go further," said Zak
Rogoff, a campaigns manager at the FSF.</p>
<p>Software patents force software developers, especially those who write
free software, to navigate a minefield of spurious legal claims. The
number of software patents has ballooned as software companies have
scrambled to amass arsenals of patents to threaten each other, as in
the recently exposed aggression by <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2014/06/chinese-govt-reveals-microsofts-secret-list-of-android-killer-patents/">Microsoft against Google over
smartphone patents</a>.</p>
<p>In the case ruled on today, Alice Corp. had claimed a patent for an
unoriginal idea, simply because it was implemented in software to run
on a computer.</p>
<p>FSF executive director John Sullivan lauded the Supreme Court for
recognizing this: "For years, lawyers have been adding 'on a computer'
to the end of abstract idea descriptions to try and turn them into
patents, much like kids have been adding 'in bed' to the end of their
fortune cookies to try and make new jokes. We're pleased to see the
Court reject this attempt and send a signal to others."</p>
<p>For decades, the FSF has argued that it is impossible to solve the
problem of software patents by getting individual software patents
struck down. The FSF will continue to work for their complete
abolition, and participate actively in future legal decisions. Those
wishing to become involved in the grassroots movement against software
patents can get started with the FSF-hosted <a href="http://endsoftpatents.org">End Software Patents</a>
project and its prominent <a href="http://en.swpat.org/wiki/Software_patents_wiki:_home_page">wiki</a>. An <a href="http://en.swpat.org/wiki/Alice_v._CLS_Bank_ruling_by_US_Supreme_Court_on_19_June_2014">analysis of the Supreme
Court's ruling</a> is currently underway on the wiki and open for
public participation.</p>
<p>Sullivan added, "Software patents are a noxious weed that needs to be
ripped out by the roots. Too many organizations are clamoring for
'reform,' thinking they can trim the weed into a Bonsai. The FSF is
one of the few organizations working for the only real
solution. Software on general-purpose computers is not patentable,
period."</p>
<h3>About the Free Software Foundation</h3>
<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development and
use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU operating
system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free documentation for free
software. The FSF also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and
political issues of freedom in the use of software, and its Web sites,
located at fsf.org and gnu.org, are an important source of information
about GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA, USA.</p>
<h3>Media Contacts</h3>
<p>Zak Rogoff<br />
Campaigns Manager<br />
Free Software Foundation<br />
+1 (617) 542 5942  <br />
<a href="mailto:campaigns@fsf.org">&#99;&#97;&#109;&#112;&#97;&#105;&#103;&#110;&#115;&#64;&#102;&#115;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a><br />
</p>
<p>###</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-06-19T21:30:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/reset-the-net">
    <title>To help Reset the Net, FSF launches guide to email protection</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/reset-the-net</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA -- Thursday, June 5th, 2014 -- The Free
Software Foundation (FSF) today released Email Self-Defense, a
how-to guide for setting up and using email encryption.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://u.fsf.org/yu">guide</a> recommends free software tools like GnuPG and Enigmail to protect
email communications from prying eyes. To accompany the guide, the FSF also released a <a href="https://u.fsf.org/yw">shareable infographic</a>.</p>
<p>The guide is being released as part of Reset the Net, a day of action
to take steps towards thwarting the government's mass surveillance
capabilities. Today's day of action marks the anniversary of the first
NSA surveillance story revealed by whistleblower Edward Snowden. Tens
of thousands of Internet activists, companies, and organizations are
taking steps to preserve free speech and basic rights on the Internet.</p>
<p>"None of the companies or governments fighting to control the Internet
treat your freedom and privacy as a priority. Maybe we can make them
change over time, but today we can act without their permission to
protect ourselves and our networks, using free software they don't
control," said John Sullivan, Free Software Foundation executive
director.</p>
<p>"The majority of email sent can be easily intercepted by any number of
people--Google will read your email to serve you ads, and the
government may read your email to keep tabs on you or someone in your
community. Today, we're making it easier for people to keep email
private, and to protect the privacy of everyone they email with. It's
up to all of us to build that web of trust, and it all starts today
with Reset the Net," said Zak Rogoff, a Free Software Foundation
campaigns manager.</p>
<h3>About the Free Software Foundation</h3>
<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development and
use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU operating
system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free documentation for free
software. The FSF also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and
political issues of freedom in the use of software, and its Web sites,
located at fsf.org and gnu.org, are an important source of information
about GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA, USA.</p>
<h3>Media Contacts</h3>
<p>Zak Rogoff<br />
Campaigns Manager <br />
Free Software Foundation<br />
+1 (617) 542 5942<br />
campaigns@fsf.org<br />
</p>
<p>###</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-06-05T14:50:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/tehnoetic-wireless-usb-adapter-now-fsf-certified-to-respect-your-freedom">
    <title>Tehnoetic wireless USB adapter now FSF-certified to respect your freedom</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/tehnoetic-wireless-usb-adapter-now-fsf-certified-to-respect-your-freedom</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA -- Wednesday, May 21, 2014 -- The Free
Software Foundation (FSF) today awarded Respects Your Freedom (RYF)
certification to the Tehnoetic TET-N150 wireless USB adapter.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The RYF certification mark is awarded to products that meet the FSF's
standards in regard to users' freedom, control over the product, and
privacy. The TET-N150 can be purchased from Tehnoetic's <a href="https://tehnoetic.com/tehnoetic-wireless-adapter-gnu-linux-libre-tet-n150">online store</a>.</p>
<p>"I founded Tehnoetic in order to give users the means to run fully
free systems and to promote ethical businesses that support the work
of the free software community. I hope that Tehnoetic will complement
and support my work at <a href="http://ceata.org">Fundația Ceata</a>, a Romanian foundation
dedicated to defending and promoting digital freedoms and aligned with
the philosophy of the GNU Project," stated Tehnoetic's founder,
Tiberiu C. Turbureanu.</p>
<p>Software certification of the device focused primarily on the firmware
for the Atheros AR9271 chip used on the adapter. This firmware is
packaged in <a href="https://www.gnu.org/s/linux-libre">Linux-libre</a>, the kernel used by several <a href="https://www.gnu.org/distros/free-distros">free
GNU/Linux</a> distributions. This is the same chipset used by the
ThinkPenguin TPE-N150USB USB wireless adapter which was also awarded
RYF certification in April 2013. While others may sell wireless USB
adapters with this same chipset, if they do not bear the RYF
certification mark, the device may be packaged with or recommend the
use of nonfree software. This is why FSF endorsement of a hardware
product is on a per seller basis rather than a blanket endorsement of
a particular hardware model or chipset.</p>
<p>"The availability of freedom-respecting wireless networking devices is
important because at present, the WiFi devices that ship with nearly
all laptops and PCs require proprietary software. This is a major
obstacle for users seeking to install a 100% free software GNU/Linux
distro, because for most people, WiFi is an essential feature. So, it
is exciting that we can now direct any such user from around the globe
to two different sellers on two different continents that offer a
small and convenient USB WiFi adapter," stated Joshua Gay, FSF
Licensing &amp; Compliance Manager. (Update: ThinkPenguin, Inc. can also ship RYF certified USB wifi adapters from Europe.)</p>
<p>To learn more about the Respects Your Freedom hardware certification,
including details on the certification of the TET-N150 wireless USB
adapter, as well as information on the driver and firmware for the
device, visit <a href="https://www.fsf.org/ryf">https://www.fsf.org/ryf</a>. Hardware sellers interested in
applying for certification can consult
<a href="https://www.fsf.org/resources/hw/endorsement/criteria">https://www.fsf.org/resources/hw/endorsement/criteria</a>.</p>
<p>Subscribers to the FSF's <a href="https://www.fsf.org/fss"><em>Free Software Supporter</em></a> newsletter
will receive announcements about future Respects Your Freedom
products.</p>
<h3>About the Free Software Foundation</h3>
<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development and
use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU operating
system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free documentation for free
software. The FSF also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and
political issues of freedom in the use of software, and its Web sites,
located at fsf.org and gnu.org, are an important source of information
about GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA, USA.</p>
<h3>About Tehnoetic</h3>
<p>Tehnoetic is a Romanian technologically ethical online shop targeting
the EU market, <a href="http://www.tehnoetic.com">http://www.tehnoetic.com</a>, and is owned and operated by
Turbureanu Tiberiu-Constantin PFA.</p>
<h3>Media Contacts</h3>
<p>Joshua Gay<br />
Licensing &amp; Compliance Manager<br />
Free Software Foundation<br />
+1 (617) 542 5942 x20<br />
<a href="mailto:licensing@fsf.org">&#108;&#105;&#99;&#101;&#110;&#115;&#105;&#110;&#103;&#64;&#102;&#115;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a><br />
</p>
<p>Tiberiu C. Turbureanu<br />
Turbureanu Tiberiu-Constantin PFA<br />
<a href="mailto:tiberiu-constantin@turbureanu.org">&#116;&#105;&#98;&#101;&#114;&#105;&#117;&#45;&#99;&#111;&#110;&#115;&#116;&#97;&#110;&#116;&#105;&#110;&#64;&#116;&#117;&#114;&#98;&#117;&#114;&#101;&#97;&#110;&#117;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a><br />
</p>
<p>###</p>
<p><em><a href="https://fsf.org/fr/tehnoetic-un-adaptateur-sans-fil-usb-certifie-fsf-qui-respecte-votre-liberte">Read this article in French</a>.</em><br />
<em><a href="https://fsf.org/ro/tehnoetic-wireless-usb-adapter-now-fsf-certified-to-respect-your-freedom-romanian">Read this article in Romanian</a>.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-05-21T21:10:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-condemns-partnership-between-mozilla-and-adobe-to-support-digital-restrictions-management">
    <title>FSF condemns partnership between Mozilla and Adobe to support Digital Restrictions Management</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-condemns-partnership-between-mozilla-and-adobe-to-support-digital-restrictions-management</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA — Wednesday, May 14th, 2014 — In response to Mozilla's announcement that it is reluctantly adopting DRM in its Firefox Web browser, Free Software Foundation executive director John Sullivan made the
following statement:</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>"Only a week after the <a href="https://defectivebydesign.org/dayagainstdrm/">International Day Against DRM</a>, Mozilla has
announced that it will partner with proprietary software company Adobe
to implement support for Web-based <a href="https://defectivebydesign.org/what_is_drm_digital_restrictions_management">Digital Restrictions
Management</a> (DRM) in its Firefox browser, using Encrypted Media
Extensions (EME).</p>

<p>The Free Software Foundation is deeply disappointed in Mozilla's
announcement. The decision compromises important principles in order
to alleviate misguided fears about loss of browser marketshare. It
allies Mozilla with a company hostile to the free software movement
and to Mozilla's own fundamental ideals.</p>

<p>Although Mozilla will not directly ship Adobe's proprietary DRM
plugin, it will, as an official feature, encourage Firefox users to
install the plugin from Adobe when presented with media that requests
DRM. We agree with Cory Doctorow that there is no meaningful
distinction between 'installing DRM' and 'installing code that
installs DRM.'</p>

<p>We recognize that Mozilla is doing this reluctantly, and we trust
these words coming from Mozilla much more than we do when they come
from Microsoft or Amazon. At the same time, nearly everyone who
implements DRM says they are forced to do it, and this lack of
accountability is how the practice sustains itself. Mozilla's
announcement today unfortunately puts it -- in this regard -- in the
same category as its proprietary competitors.</p>

<p>Unlike those proprietary competitors, Mozilla is going to great
lengths to reduce some of the specific harms of DRM by attempting to
'sandbox' the plugin. But this approach cannot solve the fundamental
ethical problems with proprietary software, or <a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/proprietary.html">the issues that
inevitably arise when proprietary software is installed</a> on a
user's computer.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2014/05/14/drm-and-the-challenge-of-serving-users/">the announcement</a>, Mitchell Baker asserts that Mozilla's hands
were tied. But she then goes on to actively praise Adobe's "value" and
suggests that there is some kind of necessary balance between DRM and
user freedom.</p>

<p>There is nothing necessary about DRM, and to hear Mozilla praising
Adobe -- the company who has been and continues to be a vicious
opponent of the free software movement and the free Web -- is
shocking. With this partnership in place, we worry about Mozilla's
ability and willingness to criticize Adobe's practices going forward.</p>

<p>We understand that Mozilla is afraid of losing users. Cory Doctorow
<a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/may/14/firefox-closed-source-drm-video-browser-cory-doctorow">points out</a> that they have produced no evidence to substantiate
this fear or made any effort to study the situation. More importantly,
popularity is not an end in itself. This is especially true for the
Mozilla Foundation, a nonprofit with an ethical mission. In the past,
Mozilla has distinguished itself and achieved success by protecting
the freedom of its users and explaining the importance of that
freedom: including publishing Firefox's source code, allowing others
to make modifications to it, and sticking to Web standards in the face
of attempts to impose proprietary extensions.</p>

<p>Today's decision turns that calculus on its head, devoting Mozilla
resources to delivering users to Adobe and hostile media
distributors. In the process, Firefox is losing the identity which set
it apart from its proprietary competitors -- Internet Explorer and
Chrome -- both of which are implementing EME in an even worse fashion.</p>

<p>Undoubtedly, some number of users just want restricted media like
Netflix to work in Firefox, and they will be upset if it doesn't. This
is unsurprising, since the majority of the world is not yet familiar
with the ethical issues surrounding proprietary software. This debate
was, and is, a high-profile opportunity to introduce these concepts to
users and ask them to stand together in some tough decisions.</p>

<p>To see Mozilla compromise without making any public effort to rally
users against this supposed "forced choice" is doubly
disappointing. They should reverse this decision. But whether they do
or do not, we call on them to join us by devoting as many of their
extensive resources to permanently eliminating DRM as they are now
devoting to supporting it. The FSF will have more to say and do on
this in the coming days. For now, users who are concerned about this
issue should:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong><a href="mailto:agal@mozilla.com">Write to Mozilla CTO Andreas Gal and let him know that you
oppose DRM</a></strong>. Mozilla made this decision in a
misguided appeal to its userbase; it needs to hear in clear and
reasoned terms from the users who feel this as a betrayal. Ask
Mozilla what it is going to do to actually solve the DRM problem that
has created this false forced choice.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="https://defectivebydesign.org/no-drm-in-html5">Join our effort to stop EME approval</a> at the W3C</strong>. While today's
announcement makes it even more obvious that W3C rejection of EME
will not stop its implementation, it also makes it clear that W3C can
fearlessly reject EME to send a message that DRM is <em>not</em> a part of
the vision of a free Web.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Use a version of Firefox without the EME code</strong>: Since its source
code is available under a license allowing anyone to modify and
redistribute it under a different name, we expect versions without
EME to be made available, and you should use those instead. We will
list them in the <a href="https://directory.fsf.org">Free Software Directory</a>.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Donate to support the work of the <a href="https://u.fsf.org/xi">Free Software Foundation</a>
and our <a href="https://u.fsf.org/xh">Defective by Design</a> campaign to actually end DRM.</strong>
Until it's completely gone, Mozilla and others will be constantly
tempted to capitulate, and users will be pressured to continue using
some proprietary software. If not us, give to another group fighting
against digital restrictions."</p></li>
</ul>

<h2>References</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://defectivebydesign.org/what_is_drm_digital_restrictions_management">What is DRM?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2014/05/14/drm-and-the-challenge-of-serving-users/">https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2014/05/14/drm-and-the-challenge-of-serving-users/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2014/05/reconciling-mozillas-mission-and-w3c-eme/">https://hacks.mozilla.org/2014/05/reconciling-mozillas-mission-and-w3c-eme/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://defectivebydesign.org/dbd-condemns-drm-in-html">https://defectivebydesign.org/dbd-condemns-drm-in-html</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fsf.org/news/coalition-against-drm-in-html">https://fsf.org/news/coalition-against-drm-in-html</a></li>
<li><a href="https://defectivebydesign.org/oscar-awarded-w3c-in-the-hollyweb">https://defectivebydesign.org/oscar-awarded-w3c-in-the-hollyweb</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>Media Contact</h2>

<p>John Sullivan <br />
Executive Director <br />
Free Software Foundation <br />
+1 (617) 542 5942 <br />
<a href="mailto:campaigns@fsf.org">campaigns@fsf.org</a></p>

<h2>About the Free Software Foundation</h2>

<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development and
use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU operating
system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free documentation for free
software. The FSF also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and
political issues of freedom in the use of software, and its Web sites,
located at fsf.org and gnu.org, are an important source of information
about GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA, USA.</p>

<p><em>This item is available in <a href="https://fsf.org/fr/la-fsf-condamne-le-partenariat-entre-mozilla-et-adobe-en-vue-de-gerer-les-dispositifs-de-gestion-numerique-des-restrictions-drm">French</a> and <a href="https://www.fsf.org/es/noticias/la-fsf-condena-la-colaboracion-entre-mozilla-y-adobe-para-apoyar-la-restriccion-digital-de-derechos-drm">Spanish</a>.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-05-14T22:35:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/global-community-rallies-for-international-day-against-drm">
    <title>Global community rallies for International Day Against DRM</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/global-community-rallies-for-international-day-against-drm</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA -- Tuesday, May 6th, 2014 -- Today a wide variety of community groups, activist organizations and businesses are taking part in the 8th International Day Against DRM (DayAgainstDRM.org). The groups are united in envisioning a world without Digital Restrictions Management, technology that places arbitrary restrictions on what people can do with digital media, often by spying on them. As the largest anti-DRM event in the world, the International Day Against DRM is an important counterpoint to the pro-DRM message broadcast by powerful media and software companies. The Day is coordinated by Defective by Design (DefectiveByDesign.org), the anti-DRM campaign of the Free Software Foundation.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>In addition to individuals taking action through <a href="http://dayagainstdrm.org">DayAgainstDRM.org</a>, nine organizations have let Defective by Design know they are participating, including three businesses offering sales on DRM-free media. Activists in Bangladesh, France and Turkey translated the <a href="http://www.defectivebydesign.org/dayagainstdrm/#graphics">International Day Against DRM HAZMAT suit graphics</a> into their native languages. More groups are expected to join on the day itself.</p>
<p>The community free software organization FOSS Bangladesh is participating for their second year. They wrote:</p>
<p>"In 2013 we joined the global community and supported International Day Against DRM. We think that IT giants' use of DRM is very wrong. To expose such wrong actions we stood out on the road at the key point of University of Dhaka and were noticed by the next generation leaders of Bangladesh, the pupils of University of Dhaka... In 2014 we are doing an open session at Daffodil University with writers, poets, novelists, artists, musicians, university students and teachers, where we hope to educate people about DRM."</p>
<p style="text-align:center"><a href="http://dayagainstdrm.org"><img src="https://static.fsf.org/nosvn/dbd/day_against_drm/2014/block/dadrm_2014_block.png" /></a></p>

<p>O'Reilly media, a major ebook publisher, is offering a steep discount on ebooks in celebration of the International Day Against DRM. They told Defective by Design:</p>
<p>"Having the ability to download files at your convenience, store them on all your devices, or share them with a friend or colleague as you would a print book or DVD is liberating, and is how it should be. At O'Reilly Media, we've always published our ebooks DRM free, following the advice of Lao Tzu, who said, 2500 years ago, '<em>Fail to honor people, they fail to honor you.</em>'"</p>
<p>John Sullivan, executive director of the Free Software Foundation, said of the International Day Against DRM: "It's exciting to see people around the world taking a stand on an issue that is so often glossed over in the public discourse. Every coordinated event that happens makes it that much harder for the press to accept DRM as business-as-usual, and gets us closer to a future without it."</p>
<p>Individuals can participate with a variety of online and in-person actions on <a href="http://dayagainstdrm.org">DayAgainstDRM.org</a>, from media downloads to gatherings. To be part of Defective by Design's year-round anti-DRM campaigns, supporters can <a href="http://www.defectivebydesign.org/join">join the low-volume Action Alerts email list</a>. Media stores, activist organizations and other groups interested in participating in the International Day Against DRM today or in 2015 should contact <a href="mailto:info@defectivebydesign.org">&#105;&#110;&#102;&#111;&#64;&#100;&#101;&#102;&#101;&#99;&#116;&#105;&#118;&#101;&#98;&#121;&#100;&#101;&#115;&#105;&#103;&#110;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a>. </p>
<h2>Participating organizations</h2>
<p>A number of groups are holding in-person events. For times and meeting places, see the <a href="https://libreplanet.org/wiki/Group:Defective_by_Design/Day_Against_DRM_2014">LibrePlanet wiki</a>.</p>
<p>In addition to Defective by Design, three activist organizations are publicly joining the Day Against DRM:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Electronic Frontier Foundation is hosting an <a href="https://www.eff.org/event/international-day-against-drm">online teach-in, writing blog posts and circulating infographics</a></li>
<li>Free Software Foundation Europe is releasing an <a href="https://fsfe.org/news/2014/news-20140506-01.en.html">open letter to the executive body of the European Union</a>, demanding that they take a stand against the groups advocating for the  addition of DRM hooks to HTML</li>
<li>April, a French free software organization, is <a href="https://www.april.org/en">blogging and raising a storm on social media</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Three online stores are participating by offering DRM-free media:</p>
<ul>
<li>O'Reilly is giving customers <a href="http://oreil.ly/DRM-FREE-2014">50-60% off on ebooks</a></li>
<li>The Humble Bundle has <a href="https://www.humblebundle.com/">pay-what-you-want graphic novels</a></li>
<li>No Starch Press is offering <a href="http://www.nostarch.com">50% off on ebooks</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>About Defective By Design</h3>
<p>Defective by Design is the Free Software Foundation's campaign against Digital Restrictions Management (DRM). DRM is the practice of imposing technological restrictions that control what users can do with digital media, creating a good that is defective by design. DRM requires the use of proprietary software and is a major threat to computer user freedom. It often spies on users as well. The campaign, based at defectivebydesign.org, organizes anti-DRM activists for in-person and online actions, and challenges powerful media and technology interests promoting DRM. Supporters can donate to the campaign at <a href="https://crm.fsf.org/civicrm/contribute/transact?reset=1&amp;id=40">https://crm.fsf.org/civicrm/contribute/transact?reset=1&amp;id=40</a>.</p>
<h3>About the Free Software Foundation</h3>
<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development and
use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU operating
system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free documentation for free
software. The FSF also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and
political issues of freedom in the use of software, and its Web sites,
located at fsf.org and gnu.org, are an important source of information
about GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA, USA.</p>
<h3>Media Contact</h3>
<p>Zak Rogoff<br />
Campaigns Manager<br />
Free Software Foundation<br />
(202) 489-6887<br />
<a href="mailto:campaigns@fsf.org">&#99;&#97;&#109;&#112;&#97;&#105;&#103;&#110;&#115;&#64;&#102;&#115;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a><br />
</p>
<p>###</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-05-06T03:56:25Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-seeks-full-time-senior-gnu-linux-systems-administrator-1">
    <title>FSF seeks full-time senior GNU/Linux systems administrator</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-seeks-full-time-senior-gnu-linux-systems-administrator-1</link>
    <description>The Free Software Foundation (FSF), a Boston-based 501(c)(3) charity
with a worldwide mission to protect freedoms critical to the
computer-using public, seeks a full-time senior systems administrator.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Update: The deadline for this position has been extended</strong></p>
<p>The ideal candidate will be a well-rounded GNU/Linux systems
administrator who thrives on constant broad-based learning and
problem-solving. (S)he will be familiar with the free software
community and how it works, and will be more interested in making a
substantial contribution to software freedom and having employment
consistent with ethical ideals than obtaining the highest salary.</p>
<p>This is an opportunity to work for the organization that started the
GNU Project, launched the free software movement, and safeguards the
GNU General Public License. The position includes frequent contact and
collaboration with many of the core GNU developers, and currently
reports to the executive director.</p>
<p>Together, the senior systems administrators have a great deal of
influence over technology decisions within the FSF, and do crucial
work empowering thousands of others to develop free software.</p>
<p>With our small staff of twelve, each person makes a clear
contribution. We work hard, but offer a humane and fun work
environment.</p>
<p>The FSF is a mature and growing organization that provides great
potential for advancement; existing staff are prioritized for any new
job openings.</p>
<h3>Example systems administration tasks include:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Be a lead voice in the Foundation's software system decision-making</li>
<li>Install and maintain fully free GNU/Linux systems on servers,
    desktops, laptops, and embedded devices</li>
<li>Support GNU developers and FSF staff in their use of FSF-owned systems</li>
<li>Monitor and improve system security and network infrastructure</li>
<li>Spec and purchase new equipment</li>
<li>Coordinate work of volunteer systems administrators</li>
<li>Share in the on-call rotation to deal with core system emergencies</li>
<li>Learn about and work with cutting-edge free technologies like Coreboot</li>
<li>Blog publicly about the technologies and techniques used at the
    FSF; inform FSF policy positions in technical areas</li>
</ul>
<h3>Programming is occasionally required, such as:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Fix bugs and submit patches upstream for the software used at the FSF</li>
<li>Design, write, and release new software when existing software doesn't fit the bill</li>
<li>Improve and maintain existing custom software</li>
</ul>
<h3>Useful specific experience includes:</h3>
<ul>
<li>4+ years experience as a GNU/Linux systems administrator</li>
<li>3+ years experience with at least two programming languages</li>
<li>2+ years experience with an apt-based GNU/Linux distribution</li>
<li>1+ years experience with SQL (preferably PostgreSQL or MySQL)</li>
<li>Undergraduate college degree, or in lieu of degree, substantially
    more experience than that listed above</li>
<li>A portfolio of contributions to free software projects or their
    development infrastructure</li>
</ul>
<h3>Expected technical skills are:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Expert knowledge of systems administration for GNU/Linux with apt-based distributions</li>
<li>In-depth understanding of key network protocols such as TCP/IP,
    BGP, DNS, SMTP, HTTP, FTP, NFS, DHCP, etc.</li>
<li>In-depth understanding of key system components such as
    virtualization, automated systems management, software RAID, MTAs,
    etc.</li>
<li>In-depth knowledge of Drupal and Nginx.</li>
<li>Familiarity with at least two of Perl, PHP, Python or Ruby. High
    proficiency (expert preferred) in at least one of these languages</li>
<li>Thorough knowledge of network and system security, especially as
    related to the kernel Linux and common Internet services</li>
<li>Knowledge of network routing and related services in GNU/Linux,
    such as iptables and stateful firewalls.</li>
<li>Ability to design SQL databases</li>
<li>Ability to spec, purchase, assemble, and debug components for
    custom-build server systems</li>
</ul>
<h3>We will prefer candidates with additional skills, such as:</h3>
<ul>
<li>In-depth knowledge of CiviCRM, Xen, Puppet, Exim, Spamassassin,
    Mailman, Quagga, Apache, RT, Coreboot, Squid, Zope, Plone,
    Semantic Mediawiki, CAS, Django, SQL Ledger</li>
<li>Knowledge of version control systems: Git, Subversion, CVS, RCS</li>
<li>Soldering, making your own Ethernet cable, extremely high Nethack scores</li>
</ul>
<h3>We also require:</h3>
<ul>
<li>A willingness to learn and understand how political and
    philosophical positions of an organization impact computing
    requirements</li>
<li>An ability to work as part of a team and to handle and coordinate
    contributions from a volunteer core</li>
<li>Being open-minded and tolerant of others</li>
</ul>
<h2>Benefits and salary</h2>
<p>The job must be worked on-site at FSF's downtown Boston offices,
because it involves caring for equipment that is physically located
there.</p>
<p>It is a union position. The salary is fixed at $61,651 and is
non-negotiable. Other benefits include:</p>
<ul>
<li>reimbursement for some relocation expenses,</li>
<li>full family health coverage through Blue Cross/Blue Shield's HMO Blue program,</li>
<li>subsidized dental plan,</li>
<li>four weeks of paid vacation annually,</li>
<li>seventeen paid holidays annually,</li>
<li>public transit commuting cost reimbursement,</li>
<li>403(b) program through TIAA-CREF,</li>
<li>yearly cost-of-living pay increases, and</li>
<li>potential for an annual performance bonus.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Application instructions</h2>
<p>The position is available immediately, and we will be accepting
applications until it is filled. </p>
<p>Applications must be submitted via email to <a href="mailto:hiring@fsf.org">&#104;&#105;&#114;&#105;&#110;&#103;&#64;&#102;&#115;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a>. The
email must contain the subject line, "Senior Systems Administrator." A
complete application should include:</p>
<ul>
<li>cover letter,</li>
<li>resume,</li>
<li>contact information for three references, and</li>
<li>links to any published free software work.</li>
</ul>
<p>All materials must be in a free format (such as plain text, PDF, or
OpenDocument, and not Microsoft Word). Email submissions that do not
follow these instructions will be overlooked. No phone calls, please.</p>
<p>An on-site interview will be required with the executive director and
the technology team.</p>
<p>We are an equal opportunity employer, committed to promoting a diverse
workplace, and do not discriminate based on gender, sex, race, color,
religion, national origin, age, disability, marital status, or sexual
orientation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-05-02T17:10:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-foundation-statement-on-heartbleed-vulnerability">
    <title>Free Software Foundation statement on Heartbleed vulnerability</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-foundation-statement-on-heartbleed-vulnerability</link>
    <description>Today, news broke of a major security vulnerability in
OpenSSL. The bug, which is being referred to as "heartbleed",
allows unauthorized access to information protected, under
normal conditions, by the SSL/TLS encryption used to secure much
of the Internet. In response to the news, Free Software
Foundation executive director John Sullivan made the following
statement:</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>

<p>Using free "as in freedom" software, like OpenSSL, is a
  necessary first step in securing our computers, our servers,
  and the entire Internet. Free software guarantees users the
  ability to examine the code in order to detect vulnerabilities,
  and to create new and safe versions if a vulnerability is
  discovered. Bugs, sometimes big ones like Heartbleed affecting
  widely used software like OpenSSL, can occur in any code, free
  or proprietary. The difference is, when no one but a
  proprietary software company like Microsoft can see the code,
  or fix it when problems are discovered, it is impossible to
  have a true chain of trust. Everyone is helpless until
  Microsoft decides to act.</p>

<p>It's been documented that companies like Microsoft are even
  <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jul/11/microsoft-nsa-collaboration-user-data">sharing bugs with others</a> like the NSA without fixing them,
  looking the other way so that third parties can exploit the
  security hole. And Apple <a href="http://www.dailydot.com/politics/nsa-backdoor-iphone-access-camera-mic-appelbaum/">has a backdoor on the iPhone</a> that
  security experts say was either caused by NSA sabotage or
  deliberate internal sabotage by Apple. In short, examples of
  proprietary software's insecurity <a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/proprietary-insecurity.html">abound</a>.</p>

<p>Heartbleed is a serious security issue, and it's a good thing
  that OpenSSL is free software. This has allowed the bug to be
  identified, and fixed rapidly after being disclosed.</p>

<p>As for the FSF's own systems, we are upgrading them as we
  speak. We'd like to thank the Trisquel<sup>‡</sup> and Debian
  distributions of GNU/Linux for quickly releasing updates with
  fixed packages.</p>

</blockquote>

<p>‡: <a href="https://trisquel.info/">Trisquel</a> is an FSF-endorsed <a href="https://www.gnu.org/distros/free-distros.html">free GNU/Linux distribution</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-04-08T22:16:02Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-award-winners-announced">
    <title>Matthew Garrett, GNOME Foundation's Outreach Program for Women are Free Software Award winners</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-award-winners-announced</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA — Saturday, March 22nd, 2014 — Free
Software Foundation president Richard M. Stallman announced the
winners of the FSF's annual Free Software Awards at a ceremony on
Saturday, March 22nd, held during the LibrePlanet 2014 conference
at MIT, in Cambridge, Massachusetts. Two awards were given: the
Award for the Advancement of Free Software, and the Award for
Projects of Social Benefit.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.fsf.org/awards/fs-award">Award for the Advancement of Free Software</a> is given
annually to an individual who has made a great contribution to
the progress and development of free software, through activities
that accord with the spirit of free software.</p>
<table cellpadding="5" cellspacing="0" width="310" border="0">
    <tr>
        <td style="padding:10px;background-color:#eeeeee;" align="center">
            <img src="//static.fsf.org/nosvn/libreplanet/2014/day1/crowd.JPG" width="600" alt="Free Software Awards at LibrePlanet 2014" />
            <div style="padding-top:10px;color:#444444">Audience members waiting for the talk</div>
        </td>
    </tr>
</table>

<p>This year, it was given to <a href="http://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/">Matthew Garrett</a>, for his work to
keep "<a href="https://www.fsf.org/campaigns/campaigns/secure-boot-vs-restricted-boot">Secure Boot</a>" free software compatible.</p>
<p>One of Garrett's nominators said, "Matthew spent considerable
efforts helping free software operating systems cope with the
UEFI 'Secure Boot' debacle.  He has also enhanced the UEFI
support in those systems, both to fix bugs and to work around
bugs in UEFI firmware.  Matthew has led the charge to develop
tools that allow users to make use of 'Secure Boot' themselves,
installing their own keys and signing their own code.  Finally,
Matthew works with the industry organizations and companies who
maintain UEFI to ensure that those standards can support free
software.  Even today, despite no longer working for a company
that requires his work in that area, he continues to serve as a
UEFI expert and debugger in his spare time."</p>
<p>Garrett said, "Free software has been a part of my life since I
was a teenager. Growing up in an area with little interest in
computing and limited internet access, having the freedom to
examine and modify the source code to software was an important
part of learning the skills I rely on today.  Everyone deserves
to be able to exercise the same freedoms that I benefited from,
and I will continue to advocate for solutions that allow them to
do so without compromising the security that recent events
demonstrate is sorely required."</p>
<p>Garrett joins a distinguished list of previous winners, including
the 2012 winner, Dr. Fernando Perez.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.fsf.org/awards/sb-award">Award for Projects of Social Benefit</a> is presented to a
project or team responsible for applying free software, or the
ideas of the free software movement, in a project that
intentionally and significantly benefits society in other aspects
of life. This award stresses the use of free software in the
service of humanity.</p>
<table cellpadding="5" cellspacing="0" width="310" border="0">
    <tr>
        <td style="padding:10px;background-color:#eeeeee;" align="center">
            <img src="//static.fsf.org/nosvn/libreplanet/2014/day1/gnome1.jpg" width="600" alt="Free Software Awards at LibrePlanet 2014" />
            <div style="padding-top:10px;color:#444444">GNOME OPW winning the Award for Projects of Social Benefit</div>
        </td>
    </tr>
</table>

<p>This year, the award went to the <a href="https://gnome.org/opw/">GNOME Foundation's Outreach
Program for Women</a> (OPW), which helps women (cis and trans)
and genderqueer people get involved in free software
development. OPW provides a supportive community for beginning to
contribute throughout the year and offers focused internship
opportunities twice a year with a number of free software
organizations. Since 2010, OPW has provided 130 women with an
opportunity to participate in paid remote internships with 23
free software organizations like Wikimedia, GNU MediaGoblin, and
last year's winner, OpenMRS. OPW's work benefits society more
broadly, addressing gender discrimination by empowering women to
develop leadership and development skills in a society which runs
on technology. OPW does this critical work using the ideals and
collaborative culture of the free software movement.</p>
<p>One nomination for the program read, "[OPW] brings women into the
free software movement who might otherwise not have become
involved, either because they believed that they weren't welcome
or that free software was just a 'boy's club.'  Given the current
number of women in the movement (approximately 2-5%), this
project is introducing free software to a largely unreached
population -- the world's women. "</p>
<p>Karen Sandler and Marina Zhurakhinskaya, co-organizers of OPW,
were present to accept the award on behalf of OPW.</p>
<p>Zhurakhinskaya, a GNOME Foundation director and community
engagement lead at Red Hat, which partners with GNOME to organize
OPW, said, "We're honored to receive this award on behalf of the
GNOME Foundation and proud that the FSF recognizes the importance
of taking action to include more women."</p>
<p>Sandler, the GNOME Foundation's executive director, said, "We
hope that this recognition inspires everyone to think about how
to improve diversity in free software. We'd love it if you'd
apply to participate, spread the word about the program, consider
joining as an organization, or ask your company to sponsor."</p>
<table cellpadding="5" cellspacing="0" width="310" border="0">
    <tr>
        <td style="padding:10px;background-color:#eeeeee;" align="center">
            <img src="//static.fsf.org/nosvn/libreplanet/2014/day1/mgarret2.jpg" width="600" alt="Free Software Awards at LibrePlanet 2014" />
            <div style="padding-top:10px;color:#444444">Matthew Garrett with his award</div>
        </td>
    </tr>
</table>

<p>Nominations for both awards are submitted by members of the
public, then evaluated by an award committee composed of previous
winners and FSF founder and president Richard Stallman. This
year's award committee was: Rob Savoye, Wietse Venema, Richard
Stallman, Suresh Ramasubramanian, Vernor Vinge, Hong Feng,
Fernanda G.  Weiden, Harald Welte, Vernor Vinge, Jonas Oberg, and
Yukihiro Matsumoto.</p>
<p>More information about both awards, including the full list of
previous winners, can be found at <a href="https://www.fsf.org/awards">https://www.fsf.org/awards</a>.</p>
<h3>About the Free Software Foundation</h3>
<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development
and use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU
operating system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free
documentation for free software. The FSF also helps to spread
awareness of the ethical and political issues of freedom in the
use of software, and its Web sites, located at fsf.org and
gnu.org, are an important source of information about
GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA, USA.</p>
<h3>Media Contacts</h3>
<p>John Sullivan<br />
Executive Director<br />
Free Software Foundation<br />
+1 (617) 542 5942<br />
<a href="mailto:campaigns@fsf.org">&#99;&#97;&#109;&#112;&#97;&#105;&#103;&#110;&#115;&#64;&#102;&#115;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a><br />
</p>
<p>Photos under CC BY 3.0
<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution</a> by Tristan Chambers. </p>
<h3></h3>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    
      <dc:subject>Advancement of Free Software</dc:subject>
    
    
      <dc:subject>Project of Social Benefit</dc:subject>
    
    
      <dc:subject>award</dc:subject>
    
    <dc:date>2014-03-22T23:10:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-joins-forces-with-software-freedom-law-center-and-open-source-initiative-to-fight-software-patents-in-u-s-supreme-court">
    <title>FSF joins forces with Software Freedom Law Center and Open Source Initiative to fight software patents in U.S. Supreme Court  </title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-joins-forces-with-software-freedom-law-center-and-open-source-initiative-to-fight-software-patents-in-u-s-supreme-court</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA -- Friday, February 28, 2014 -- The Free
Software Foundation (FSF) joined the Software Freedom Law Center
(SFLC) and the Open Source Initiative (OSI) in filing a brief
amici curiae in software patent case Alice Corp. v. CLS Bank
before the United States Supreme Court yesterday.
</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The jointly filed <a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2014/alice_v_cls-sflc_amicus.pdf">brief</a> argues that the "machine or transformation"
inquiry employed by the Court in <em>Bilski v. Kappos</em> is the correct,
and exclusive, bright line test for patent eligibility of
computer-implemented inventions. It says that not only do software
idea patents fail established tests for patentability; they also
violate the First Amendement.</p>
<p>On March 31, 2014, the Supreme Court of the United States will hear
oral arguments in the case, in which the Court has granted certiorari,
apparently to decide a question previously reserved: under what
circumstances patents may be granted for inventions implemented in
computer programs. A decision is expected by summer.</p>
<p>FSF executive director John Sullivan added, "We are proud to be a
party to SFLC's brief, along with OSI. Software patents should be
opposed not just by <em>all</em> computer programmers and users; they should
be opposed by anyone who values freedom of expression. We've seen many
recent proposals to make software idea patents 'better,' or to fight
trolls, but they miss the fundamental point. We do not want these
restrictions on free speech and human creative expression to be of
higher quality -- we want software idea patents gone."</p>
<p>The FSF has been campaigning for decades to abolish software idea
patents. Its <a href="http://endsoftpatents.org/">End Software Patents</a> campaign filed a <a href="http://www.fsf.org/news/bilski-supreme-court-brief">brief in the
<em>Bilski</em> case</a>, and released a <a href="http://patentabsurdity.com">documentary film</a> detailing the
problem. The campaign's <a href="http://en.swpat.org/wiki/Software_patents_wiki:_home_page">wiki</a> has continued to grow as a
preeminent source of legislative, judicial, and philosophical
information in the area.</p>
<p>FSF president Richard M. Stallman regularly <a href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/software-patents.html">speaks out against
software patents</a>, often highlighting their absurdity by imagining
how we would feel about similar <a href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/software-literary-patents.html">patents on literature</a>.</p>
<h3>About the Free Software Foundation</h3>
<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development and
use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU operating
system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free documentation for free
software. The FSF also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and
political issues of freedom in the use of software, and its Web sites,
located at fsf.org and gnu.org, are an important source of information
about GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA, USA.</p>
<h3>Media Contacts</h3>
<p>John Sullivan<br />
Executive Director<br />
Free Software Foundation<br />
+1 (617) 542 5942<br />
<a href="mailto:campaigns@fsf.org">&#99;&#97;&#109;&#112;&#97;&#105;&#103;&#110;&#115;&#64;&#102;&#115;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a><br />
</p>
<p>###</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-02-28T22:39:52Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-foundation-opens-registration-for-march-24th-legal-seminar-on-gpl-enforcement-and-legal-ethics">
    <title>Free Software Foundation opens registration for March 24th legal seminar on GPL Enforcement and Legal Ethics</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-foundation-opens-registration-for-march-24th-legal-seminar-on-gpl-enforcement-and-legal-ethics</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA -- Friday, February 14th, 2014 -- The Free
Software Foundation (FSF) today announced open registration
for a seminar on GPL Enforcement and Legal Ethics, to be held Monday, March
24th, 2014, at Suffolk University Law School. The half-day seminar
will provide an introduction to the terms of the GNU General Public License (GPL), a detailed look at
how it can and has been enforced, and a session on professional ethics considerations
for lawyers working with clients involved in free software.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The event sessions will be lead
by Karen Sandler of the GNOME Foundation and former general counsel of
the Software Freedom Law Center; Bradley Kuhn, President of
the Software Freedom Conservancy and a member of the FSF's Board of Directors, and Donald
R. Robertson, III, J.D., the FSF's Copyright and Licensing Associate.</p>
<p>The event is aimed at legal professionals and law students. Registration for the event is open to the public at <a href="https://crm.fsf.org/civicrm/event/register?reset=1&amp;id=15">https://crm.fsf.org/civicrm/event/register?reset=1&amp;id=15</a>.</p>
<p>"We're looking forward to helping current and future lawyers get comfortable working with the GNU General Public License and other free software licenses, so that they can expand their practices and address their clients' concerns," said FSF executive director John Sullivan.</p>
<p>The seminar is scheduled for the day after the Free Software
Foundation's <a href="http://libreplanet.org/2014/">LibrePlanet 2014 conference</a>, an annual conference that brings
together software developers, policy experts, activists and computer
users to learn skills, share accomplishments and face challenges to
software freedom.</p>
<p>More information about the event can be found at the <a href="https://www.fsf.org/events/seminar-on-gpl-enforcement-and-legal-ethics">event page</a>.</p>
<h3>About the Free Software Foundation</h3>
<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development and
use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU operating
system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free documentation for free
software. The FSF also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and
political issues of freedom in the use of software, and its Web sites,
located at fsf.org and gnu.org, are an important source of information
about GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA, USA.</p>
<h3>Presenters</h3>
<h4>Bradley M. Kuhn</h4>
<p><a href="http://ebb.org/bkuhn/">Bradley M. Kuhn</a> is President
of the <a href="http://sfconservancy.org/">Software Freedom Conservancy</a>
and on the Board of Directors of
the <a href="http://fsf.org/">Free Software Foundation (FSF)</a>. Kuhn began his
work in the software freedom movement as a volunteer in 1992, when he
became an early adopter of the GNU/Linux operating system, and began
contributing to various FLOSS projects. He worked during the 1990s as a
system administrator and software developer for various companies, and
taught AP Computer Science at Walnut Hills High School in Cincinnati.
Kuhn's non-profit career began in 2000, when he was hired by the FSF.
As FSF's Executive Director from 2001-2005, Kuhn led FSF's GPL
enforcement, launched its Associate Member program, and invented the
Affero GPL.  From 2005-2010, Kuhn worked as the Policy Analyst and
Technology Director of the Software Freedom Law Center.  Kuhn holds a
summa cum laude B.S. in Computer Science from
<a href="http://www.loyola.edu/academic/computerscience">Loyola University in Maryland</a>, and an
M.S. in Computer Science from the <a href="http://www.cs.uc.edu/">University of Cincinnati</a>.
<a href="http://www.ebb.org/bkuhn/articles/thesis/">Kuhn's Master's thesis</a> discussed methods for
dynamic interoperability of FLOSS languages. Kuhn has
<a href="http://ebb.org/bkuhn/blog">a blog</a> and <a href="http://identi.ca/bkuhn">a microblog as @bkuhn
on identi.ca</a>.</p>
<h4>Karen M. Sandler</h4>
<p>Karen M. Sandler is the Executive Director of the GNOME Foundation. She is known for her advocacy for free software, particularly for software safety on medical devices. Prior to joining GNOME, she was General Counsel of the <a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/">Software Freedom Law Center</a>. Karen continues to do pro bono legal work with SFLC and serves as an officer of the <a href="https://sfconservancy.org/">Software Freedom Conservancy</a>. She is also pro bono General Counsel of <a href="http://questioncopyright.org/">QuestionCopyright.org</a> and an advisor to the Ada Initiative. Before joining SFLC, Karen worked as an associate in the corporate departments of Gibson, Dunn &amp; Crutcher LLP in New York and Clifford Chance in New York and London. Karen received her law degree from Columbia Law School in 2000, where she was a James Kent Scholar and co-founder of the Columbia Science and Technology Law Review. Karen received her bachelors degree in engineering from The Cooper Union. She is a recipient of the O'Reilly Open Source Award.</p>
<h4>Donald R. Robertson, III</h4>
<p>Donald R. Robertson, III, is the Copyright and Licensing Associate for the Free Software Foundation, where he has worked for over five years as part of the FSF's Licensing &amp; Compliance Lab. He is actively involved in the FSF's compliance work, and is one of the FSF's primary representatives in conversations with companies whose employees want to contribute to free software projects. Donald is a graduate of the New England School of Law, where he was the managing editor of the <em>New England Law Review</em>, and interned for the Hon. William G. Young at the federal district courthouse in Boston. He received his bachelors degree in philosophy and history from Cornell College, and is admitted to the Massachusetts bar.</p>
<h3>Media Contacts</h3>
<p>Joshua Gay<br />
Licensing &amp; Compliance Manager<br />
Free Software Foundation<br />
+1 (617) 542 5942<br />
<a href="mailto:licensing@fsf.org">&#108;&#105;&#99;&#101;&#110;&#115;&#105;&#110;&#103;&#64;&#102;&#115;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a></p>
<p>###</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-02-15T01:08:53Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/lulzbot-taz-3-3d-printer-now-fsf-certified-to-respect-your-freedom">
    <title>LulzBot TAZ 3 3D printer now FSF-certified to respect your freedom</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/lulzbot-taz-3-3d-printer-now-fsf-certified-to-respect-your-freedom</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA -- Friday, February 7, 2014 -- The Free
Software Foundation (FSF) today awarded Respects Your Freedom (RYF)
certification to the TAZ 3, the fifth model in the LulzBot line of 3D
printers by Aleph Objects, Inc.  The RYF certification mark means that
the product meets the FSF's standards in regard to users' freedom,
control over the product, and privacy.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img src="//static.fsf.org/nosvn/ryf/taz3.jpg" width="150" style="padding:10px;float:right" class="imgright" />

<p>In October 2012, the LulzBot AO-100 3D printer became the first
hardware product to be awarded use of the FSF's <a href="https://www.fsf.org/ryf">RYF</a> certification
mark. Since that time, Aleph Objects, Inc. has continued to release
new and improved successors to the AO-100 model, including the AO-101,
TAZ, TAZ 2, and TAZ 3, each of which have complied with RYF
certification mark requirements. The latest model, which can be
purchased <a href="http://www.lulzbot.com/products/lulzbot-taz-3-3d-printer">online</a>,
has both hardware and software improvements, including a controller with
a graphical LCD interface that allows users to print from an SD card and to
perform printer start up, selection, and configuration changes.</p>
<p>"Aleph Objects, Inc. has become a leader in the free software
movement, not only in terms of producing hardware products that
respect users' freedom, but also in terms of their engagement with and
contributions to the free software community each step of the way,"
said Joshua Gay, FSF licensing &amp; compliance manager.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://download.lulzbot.com/TAZ/3.0/software/2013Q4/">software reviewed</a> by Gay as part of the certification for the
TAZ 3 printer includes the Marlin firmware for the RAMBo electronics
board and ATmega chipset; the Python printing host software suite,
which includes Pronterface, Pronsole, and Printcore; and a Slic3r, a
program used to convert a digital 3D models into printing
instructions.</p>
<p>"Aleph Objects, Inc. is honored to receive RYF certification for our
latest 3D printer, the TAZ 3. No organization has greater credibility
when it comes to user freedom than the Free Software Foundation, which
for nearly thirty years has been prescient about technology issues
that threaten user freedom. Our goal is to continue to practice these
principles as we develop new technology," said Jeff Moe, president of Aleph
Objects, Inc.</p>
<p>In addition to the the LulzBot line of 3D printers, a total of nine
products have been awarded use of the RYF certification mark,
including: the RAMBo all-in-one 3D printer electronics board used in
the LulzBot printers; two USB wireless adapters sold by ThinkPenguin;
and the Gluglug X60 laptop.</p>
<p>To learn more about the Respects Your Freedom hardware certification
program visit <a href="https://www.fsf.org/ryf">https://www.fsf.org/ryf</a>.</p>
<p>Hardware sellers interested in applying for certification can consult
<a href="https://www.fsf.org/resources/hw/endorsement/criteria">https://www.fsf.org/resources/hw/endorsement/criteria</a>.</p>
<h3>About the Free Software Foundation</h3>
<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development and
use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU operating
system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free documentation for free
software. The FSF also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and
political issues of freedom in the use of software, and its Web sites,
located at fsf.org and gnu.org, are an important source of information
about GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA, USA.</p>
<h3>About Aleph Objects, Inc.</h3>
<p>Built upon the philosophy of <em>freedom</em>, Aleph Objects, Inc. is
transforming the 3D printer industry. Based in Loveland, Colo., they
are committed to Libre Hardware, which means their hardware and
software will not be locked down, become obsolete, or require licensed
upgrades over time. Empowering customers is part of their innovative
spirit and LulzBot users are encouraged to be part of the ongoing
conversation. Join in and learn more online at <a href="http://lulzbot.com">http://lulzbot.com</a>.</p>
<h3>Media Contacts</h3>
<p>Joshua Gay<br />
Licensing &amp; Compliance Manager<br />
Free Software Foundation<br />
+1 (617) 542 5942<br />
licensing@fsf.org</p>
<p>Kristin Golliher<br />
Media Contact, LulzBot/Aleph Objects, Inc.<br />
(970) 449 6870<br />
Kristin.Golliher@wildrockpr.com<br />
www.LulzBot.com</p>
<h3></h3>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-02-10T16:03:15Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/anti-fast-track-mobilization-to-be-extended-after-more-than-half-a-million-people-take-action">
    <title>Anti-Fast Track mobilization to be extended after more than half a million people take action</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/anti-fast-track-mobilization-to-be-extended-after-more-than-half-a-million-people-take-action</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA -- Wednesday, February 5th, 2014 --
Yesterday, a diverse network of organizations opposing Fast Track
legislation, including the Free Software Foundation, announced
they are extending their ten days of activism following massive
and widespread public action. Since its inception on January
22nd, more than a hundred new groups have joined the effort at
StopFastTrack.com, including Coalition for a Prosperous
America, Ben &amp; Jerry's, SumOfUs, Democracy for America, Friends
of the Earth, Namecheap, and CREDO -- adding to an already
impressive, and unlikely, list of groups like reddit, Sierra
Club, AFL-CIO, MoveOn, LabelGMOs, and Fight for the Future.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The campaign has been embraced by more than 120 organizations and
coincided with more than <a href="http://tradejustice.ca/tpp/jan31">fifty rallies</a> and teach-ins across
the U.S., Canada and Mexico last week alone. Nearly six hundred
thousand people have signed petitions or sent emails to
lawmakers, and members of Congress have already received more
than forty thousand phone calls from constituents who oppose Fast
Track.</p>
<p>"When we launched this effort about ten days ago, we had twenty
groups participating -- now we have 120," said Evan Greer,
campaign manager at Fight for the Future, the Internet freedom
group that helped initiate the <a href="http://stopfasttrack.com">StopFastTrack.com</a>
effort. "It's time for those in power to read the writing on the
wall; people from across the political spectrum overwhelmingly
oppose anti-democratic Fast Track legislation, and we won't allow
decisions that affect all of us to be made behind closed doors."</p>
<p><a href="http://stopfasttrack.com">See the full list of 120 organizations participating</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://stopfasttrack.com/#photos">See photos from more than fifty protests and events</a>.</p>
<p>Last week a nationwide, <a href="http://fasttrackpoll.info">bipartisan poll</a> found that voters
oppose fast track authority by more than two to one. The poll
also found that members of Congress who vote to approve Fast
Track -- especially Republicans -- are taking a political risk.</p>
<p>The massive mobilization from Fast Track opponents has clearly
made an impact in Washington, with Senate Majority leader Harry
Reid coming out in opposition to Fast Track, but organizers
caution that the fight is not over. They plan a public petition
delivery in the coming weeks to increase pressure on Congress to
oppose the Fast Track bill.</p>
<p>"With TPP, special interests are gunning for draconian copyright
rules that would entrench Digital Restrictions Management (DRM)
and chill the development of the free "as-in-freedom" software we
need," said John Sullivan, executive director of the Free
Software Foundation, "We're inspired to be part of such a diverse
outcry against the Fast Track. It's clear that people see the
damage that TPP's restrictions would do to freedom and culture."</p>
<p>"The only way we're going to stop the secret corporate power grab
known as the Trans-Pacific Partnership is if we stop Fast
Track. That's why we're proud to stand with the scores of other
organizations who are engaged in this fight," said Becky Bond,
political director of CREDO. "When so many organizations with
diverse backgrounds and concerns stand together, it sends a
powerful message. If you think the American people will allow
Congress to abdicate its responsibility by passing Fast Track,
prepare to be disappointed."</p>
<p>Michael Stumo, CEO of the Coalition for a Prosperous America,
stated: "Our members oppose giving President Obama even more
executive authority through Fast Track.  We need a new trade
agenda to balance trade and to prevent further outsourcing our
sovereignty to international institutions.  We will be watching
Tea Party caucus members to make sure they do not favor these
global government agreements."</p>
<p>David Cascino, CEO of Thunderclap, stated: "Now that people can
rapidly organize around social media, phone call campaigns and
targeted emails, it's getting increasingly difficult for
politicians to make decisions behind closed doors."</p>
<p>Steve Anderson, executive director of OpenMedia.org said: "We
know that the TPP will make the Internet more expensive,
censored, and policed. That's why hundreds of thousands are
speaking out to stop it being rammed through Congress without a
debate. It's never been more important to pick up the phone and
tell your Member of Congress to stop Fast Tracking a deal that
would criminalize your online activity, invade your privacy, and
cost you money."</p>
<p>"The breadth of opposition to Fast Tracking the TPP in any form
whatsoever shows that the people will not be fooled by rigged
corporate trade agreements. The TPP is so bad that it unites
people in vehement opposition -- entire cities and towns are
already saying that they will not obey laws passed in secret that
will harm them. If Congress moves forward on Fast Track, we
expect growing resistance that will include disruption of
re-election campaigns." said Dr. Margaret Flowers of
PopularResistance.org, an outgrowth of the Occupy Movement.</p>
<p>"Rainforest Action Network seeks to challenge corporate power
where it undermines the interests of people and planet," said
Lindsey Allen, executive director of Rainforest Action
Network (RAN)."The TPP is a profit-driven frontal assault on
democracy and issues core to RAN's work and in a time where we
need every tool necessary to address global climate disruption,
it is unacceptable to use an undemocratic shortcut like Fast
Track to force through the TPP and usurp the interests of
millions."</p>
<p>Communications Workers of America president Larry Cohen
said, "Voters across the political spectrum are energized. They
know this deal affects everybody - small business, workers,
anyone who cares about about the food we eat, the air we breathe,
and the jobs we hold. Americans are asking what kind of future do
we want? We don't want a trillion-dollar trade deficit.  We need
to reset our trade policy, so that it works for everyone, not
just big corporations."</p>
<p>"The Obama administration's plan to ram two potentially
devastating international trade agreements through Congress
appears to be slowing down thanks to widespread opposition, but
we're not taking any chances," said Ronnie Cummins International
director of the Organic Consumers Association. "We must stop
trade deals that would weaken U.S. and world food safety
standards, threaten domestic and international food sovereignty
laws, and allow transnational corporations to sue governments for
alleged future lost profits unless the corporations are allowed
to freely peddle their unproven, unsafe goods with reckless
regard for existing food safety laws."</p>
<p>Richard Trumka, president of the AFL-CIO, said, "The widespread interest in
"Fast Track" from across the political spectrum is no surprise.
It's only more evidence of what America's workers have known for
a long time: America's workforce deserves better than warmed over
trade deals, which will do nothing to raise wages or reduce our
$540 billion trade deficit.  The United States is long overdue
for an overhaul of its trade priorities and trade practices and
that can only happen with an inclusive process that includes all
our voices, not just the disproportionate influence of the 1%."</p>
<p>"Fast Track authority takes democratic process away from our
elected representatives, striking any discussion or debate on
trade agreements in Congress, for example, on the upcoming
Trans-Pacific Partnership," says Carleen Pickard, executive
director of Global Exchange. "Fast Tracking" such an agreement
without substantive discussion about it's impacts is a bad idea".</p>
<p>"Imports increased three times faster than exports since NAFTA took effect,
and our trade deficit is devastating to American workers," said
Teamsters General president Jim Hoffa. "Congress should read
every word of these so-called 'free-trade deals' to make sure
they help American families and to get rid of special deals
inserted by corporate lobbyists."</p>
<p>Elizabeth Warren, MoveOn National TPP team coordinator
said, "MoveOn's TPP team is committed to fighting Fast Track in
Congress. While we long for good news, and it is tempting to be
reassured by Senator Reid's comments, we need to differentiate
between rhetoric and action. His statements could be the opening
salvo in a debate over Democratic amendments to the Baucus bill,
or he could be setting the stage for an alternate version of Fast
Track - traveling under an assumed name - to be sponsored by Ron
Wyden, for example. We must remain focused, and continue
pressuring House members until a wide majority unequivocally
oppose it - on the record - in ANY form."</p>
<p>"Across the country, Sierra Club members and supporters are ready
to stand up for responsible trade that doesn't threaten American
jobs, our air and water, and our climate," said Michael Brune,
Sierra Club executive director. "The Sierra Club strongly opposes
fast track.  This bill not only undermines our democracy, it puts
American families and our future at risk."</p>
<h3></h3>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2014-02-05T23:48:42Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/gift-giving-gnu-advises-shoppers-to-give-freely">
    <title>Gift giving gnu advises shoppers to "give freely"</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/gift-giving-gnu-advises-shoppers-to-give-freely</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA -- Friday, December 20th, 2013 --
Yesterday, Free Software Foundation activists visited the Boston
Apple store to raise awareness of more ethical alternatives for
technology gifts. The activists were accompanied by a gnu (the free
software movement's buffalo-like mascot) and sported Santa hats in the
spirit of the season. Shoppers were surprised to see such an
unusual Santa, and many took stickers and copies of the
FSF's "Giving Guide," which contains tips for purchasing tech
gifts that respect computer users' freedom, privacy and security.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img src="https://static.fsf.org/nosvn/images/givingguideaction2013/IMG_9211.JPG" style="padding:10px;float:left" width="265" />

<p>The Giving Guide, which is available <a href="https://www.fsf.org/givingguide">online</a>, suggests laptops, ebooks, 3D
printers, and more gift ideas while discouraging shoppers from
purchasing products with problems like proprietary software,
hardware locked down with digital handcuffs, or ebooks that contain Digital
Restrictions Management (DRM).</p>
<p>FSF executive director John Sullivan said, "This year we know
it's not just Santa who's making a list--the NSA is watching you,
too. Make sure that your holiday gift is free of back doors,
security loopholes, and keeps your loved ones' personal
information private. Our Giving Guide will help you choose
alternatives to bad products like Windows 8 and Macbooks, and
give you tips for moving towards software freedom."</p>
<p>The Boston Apple store is one the largest in the world. Apple is
known as one of the world's worst patent aggressors, and its
computers, tablets, and cell phones run on restrictive
proprietary software.</p>
<p>The FSF asks supporters to keep their eyes peeled for more
appearances by the gnu in coming months.</p>
<h3>About the Free Software Foundation</h3>
<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development
and use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU
operating system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free
documentation for free software. The FSF also helps to spread
awareness of the ethical and political issues of freedom in the
use of software, and its Web sites, located at fsf.org and
gnu.org, are an important source of information about
GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA,
USA.</p>
<h3>About the GNU Operating System and Linux</h3>
<p>Richard Stallman announced in September 1983 the plan to develop
a free software Unix-like operating system called GNU. GNU is the
only operating system developed specifically for the sake of
users' freedom. See <a href="https://www.gnu.org/gnu/the-gnu-project.html">https://www.gnu.org/gnu/the-gnu-project.html</a>.</p>
<p>In 1992, the essential components of GNU were complete, except
for one, the kernel. When in 1992 the kernel Linux was
re-released under the GNU GPL, making it free software, the
combination of GNU and Linux formed a complete free operating
system, which made it possible for the first time to run a PC
without non-free software. This combination is the GNU/Linux
system. For further explanation, see
<a href="https://www.gnu.org/gnu/gnu-linux-faq.html">https://www.gnu.org/gnu/gnu-linux-faq.html</a>.</p>
<h3>Media Contacts</h3>
<p>Zak Rogoff and Libby Reinish<br />
Campaigns Managers<br />
Free Software Foundation<br />
+1 (617) 542 5942<br />
<a href="mailto:campaigns@fsf.org">&#99;&#97;&#109;&#112;&#97;&#105;&#103;&#110;&#115;&#64;&#102;&#115;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a><br />
</p>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2013-12-20T21:48:35Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/gluglug-x60-laptop-now-certified-to-respect-your-freedom">
    <title>Gluglug X60 Laptop now certified to Respect Your Freedom</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/gluglug-x60-laptop-now-certified-to-respect-your-freedom</link>
    <description>BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA -- Thursday, December 19, 2013 -- The Free
Software Foundation (FSF) today awarded Respects Your Freedom (RYF)
certification to Gluglug X60 laptops. The RYF certification mark means
that the product meets the FSF's standards in regard to users'
freedom, control over the product, and privacy. This is the first
laptop to receive RYF certification from the FSF.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img class="imgright" src="//static.fsf.org/nosvn/ryf/ryf-x60-1.jpg" width="200/" />

<p>It can be purchased from <a href="http://shop.gluglug.org.uk">http://shop.gluglug.org.uk</a>.</p>
<p>The FSF has had a call out for a laptop sold with a free OS and <a href="http://www.fsf.org/campaigns/free-bios.html">free
boot system</a> since 2005.
Today it announced that the call has been met.</p>
<p>"Finally there is a free software laptop that respects your freedom as
it comes from the store," stated Richard M. Stallman, founder and
president of the FSF.</p>
<p>The boot programs (such as a BIOS) run when a computer is turned on
and their primary purpose is to initialize the hardware before loading
the operating system. Computer makers not only install nonfree boot
programs, but they also have made it notoriously difficult for free
software developers to have access to the necessary hardware
specifications and information needed to produce free software
replacements.</p>
<p>When a user purchases a product that bears the Respects Your Freedom
certification mark, they can be confident they are receiving a product
that comes with a free boot program and OS, as well as documentation
under free licenses, multimedia unencumbered by proprietary formats,
and the assurance it is not known to contain any backdoors and is not
designed to share users' information without their knowledge (e.g.
spyware).</p>
<p>"This announcement comes at a time when people have a heightened
concern over controlling their data and securing their communication.
Proprietary software is by nature fundamentally insecure, because it
uses both force of law and technological measures to prohibit a user
from controlling and securing her own computer. This new complete
system runs on free software and is backed by the FSF's commitment to
do our best at ensuring respect for your freedom and privacy," said
FSF executive director John Sullivan.</p>
<p>The Gluglug X60 laptops are refurbished models of Lenovo's
ThinkPad®<sup>†</sup> X60. Gluglug has updated the computer by adding
a modern wifi chipset, replacing the proprietary BIOS with a free
software boot system made by modifying Coreboot to remove all
proprietary microcode and proprietary blobs, and replacing the
proprietary Microsoft Windows OS with the FSF-endorsed, <a href="http://trisquel.info/">Trisquel
GNU/Linux</a> OS.</p>
<p>"The Gluglug X60 laptop is a major victory for computer users and
supporters of the <em>Free BIOS</em> campaign. Not only has Gluglug produced
a 100% free version of Coreboot that carries freedom to each user, but
it has made it easy and fun to install updates, which in my
experience, make real and noticeable improvements to the operation of
the laptop. I also found that despite the hardware being a few years
old, the Gluglug X60 remains a durable machine that is more than
capable of running modern GNU/Linux distro," added Joshua Gay, the
licensing &amp; compliance manager who heads-up the FSF's RYF
certification program.</p>
<p>Francis Rowe of Gluglug issued the following statement:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Gluglug is very proud to have achieved RYF certification and we will
always try to exceed the requirements. The mission of Gluglug is to
promote free software in a practical way by making it easy to find a
system built for total freedom. With the X60 laptops sold through
the site you get everything: free boot program, free operating
system, free drivers, free applications. The machines also come
pre-fitted with a new 802.11n wireless card that is fully compatible
with free software.</p>
<p>The machines come fully loaded with Trisquel GNU/Linux, and they can
also have <a href="http://www.gnewsense.org/">gNewSense</a> or <a href="https://parabolagnulinux.org/">Parabola
GNU/Linux</a> installed on request. With
the Gluglug X60, you get full source code for all of the tools used
to create the boot program, plus documentation. If you want to hack
your machine, you can. That's really the whole concept.</p>
<p>You also get updates, so when the Gluglug makes a substantial change
to the firmware it ships, you will receive a copy of it along with
documentation for how to flash it and tweak it to your needs.</p>
<p>A project like this is especially important in this day and age when
more and more devices are becoming locked down with things like
<a href="http://www.fsf.org/campaigns/secure-boot-vs-restricted-boot">Restricted Boot</a>,
and containing hardware-based backdoors. The Gluglug provides an
opt-out for that kind of mistreatment.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>To learn more about the Respects Your Freedom hardware certification,
including details on the certification of the Gluglug X60 laptops, as
well as information on source code for the device, visit
<a href="http://www.fsf.org/ryf">http://www.fsf.org/ryf</a>. Hardware sellers interested in applying for
certification can consult criteria at
<a href="http://www.fsf.org/resources/hw/endorsement/criteria">http://www.fsf.org/resources/hw/endorsement/criteria</a>.</p>
<p>For those needing to purchase other hardware, the FSF recommends
<a href="http://www.fsf.org/news/h-node.org">http://h-node.org</a> database, as well as direct users
toward hardware sellers that offer laptops with GNU/Linux
preinstalled. The FSF is also asking supporters
<a href="http://www.fsf.org/campaigns/free-bios.html">to write to Intel</a>
asking for the company to ship laptops with a free boot system to
begin with, so that users can buy brand new freedom-respecting
hardware in the future.</p>
<h3>About the Free Software Foundation</h3>
<p>The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to
promoting computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs. The FSF promotes the development and
use of free (as in freedom) software -- particularly the GNU operating
system and its GNU/Linux variants -- and free documentation for free
software. The FSF also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and
political issues of freedom in the use of software, and its Web sites,
located at fsf.org and gnu.org, are an important source of information
about GNU/Linux. Donations to support the FSF's work can be made at
<a href="https://donate.fsf.org">https://donate.fsf.org</a>. Its headquarters are in Boston, MA, USA.</p>
<h3>About Gluglug</h3>
<p>The Gluglug is a Canvey Island, Essex, UK based company dedicated to
Free Software.  We sell computers that are made to respect the freedom
of users to study and hack their machine. Visit
<a href="http://shop.gluglug.org.uk">http://shop.gluglug.org.uk</a>.</p>
<h3>Media Contacts</h3>
<p>Joshua Gay<br />
Licensing &amp; Compliance Manager<br />
Free Software Foundation<br />
+1 (617) 542 5942<br />
<a href="mailto:licensing@fsf.org">&#108;&#105;&#99;&#101;&#110;&#115;&#105;&#110;&#103;&#64;&#102;&#115;&#102;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;</a><br />
</p>
<p>Francis Rowe<br />
Founder &amp; CEO<br />
Gluglug<br />
<a href="mailto:info@gluglug.org.uk">&#105;&#110;&#102;&#111;&#64;&#103;&#108;&#117;&#103;&#108;&#117;&#103;&#46;&#111;&#114;&#103;&#46;&#117;&#107;</a><br />
</p>
<p><sup>†</sup>ThinkPad is a registered trademark of Lenovo.</p>
<h3></h3>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2013-12-19T20:30:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>


  <item rdf:about="http://www.fsf.org/news/reform-corporate-surveillance">
    <title>Reform corporate surveillance</title>
    <link>http://www.fsf.org/news/reform-corporate-surveillance</link>
    <description>The FSF issued the following statement in response to the recent open letter on government surveillance published by AOL, Apple, Facebook, Google, LinkedIn, Microsoft, Twitter, and Yahoo.</description>
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>A group of technology companies, most of whom were implicated in
handing user information over to the NSA, recently <a href="https://reformgovernmentsurveillance.com/">came together to ask
world governments</a> to reform
the way they conduct surveillance, according to a set of principles.</p>

<p>Free Software Foundation executive director John Sullivan made the following statement:</p>

<p>"The Free Software Foundation may support one or more of the measures
proposed to 'reform government surveillance.' We may end up working
with this coalition of companies, after we have had a chance to review
and discuss with them what they are advocating. It is encouraging to
see recognition from the coalition about one side of the surveillance
issue.</p>

<p>However, this problem is not one that can be solved through government
reform alone, and there is a danger that focus on these reforms will
be flypaper that drains energy for more fundamental change. In
addition to policy reform, we must have software reform.</p>

<p>In the US, there were <em>already</em> policies and laws against many
revealed spy agency behaviors. These rules are being ignored, or
interpreted in ways that maximize surveillance.</p>

<p>The surveillance is actively enabled by these companies' software and
technology. Microsoft Windows provides back doors for the NSA.
Companies like Google and Facebook build their businesses on the model
of consolidating huge amounts of user data, enabling mining of that
data, and pulling users away from software run on their own computers
to software that is remotely hosted.</p>

<p>Nowhere on the coalition site, or in the open letter, do any of
the companies take any responsibility for what is happening. Yet, they
have intentionally put their users in a vulnerable position, and
exploited them without hesitation. They use copyright, patents, and
contracts to insist that the software they publish be proprietary. Or,
instead of distributing software at all, they provide it as a hosted
'service.'</p>

<p>Both have the same negative implications for users. The very people
using this software are not allowed to see what it is actually doing,
nor can they ask for someone else <em>of their choosing</em> to review it on
their behalf. The result is a computer that in the end serves only the
company who 'owns' the software -- and the governments with whom they
choose to share information, or anyone who can find their way to the
backdoors.</p>

<p>Furthermore, users need to worry not just about how their information
is accessed by the government. They are also entitled to control how
it is accessed by corporations. Corporate employees can abuse data in
many of the very same ways NSA employees have.</p>

<p>While these companies voice their support for legislative changes they
think will address the problem, they continue to drive technology
which is on face damaging to everyone's privacy, freedom, and
security.</p>

<p>We call on these companies to issue an additional set of principles
declaring their support for user control over the software and
computers they use. We need a
<a href="http://reformcorporatesurveillance.org">http://reformcorporatesurveillance.org</a>. </p>

<p>Until they do so, they can at best be allies of convenience in this
effort. We might support their ideas for new laws, but we must be
careful not to invest public resources inventing new policy band-aids
to cover wounds they are perpetually re-opening. We won't let this
distract us from their ongoing culpability, or the need for radical
software reform."</p>

<h3>For more information</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-responds-to-microsofts-privacy-and-encryption-announcement">"FSF responds to Microsoft's privacy and encryption announcement"</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.wired.com/opinion/2013/10/a-necessary-evil-what-it-takes-for-democracy-to-survive-surveillance/">"How much surveillance can democracy withstand?"</a> by Richard M. Stallman</li>
<li><a href="https://gnu.org/philosophy/proprietary.html">Examples of abuses committed via proprietary software</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.fsf.org/campaigns/surveillance">FSF's campaign against surveillance</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/who-does-that-server-really-serve.html">"Who does that server really serve?"</a> by Richard M. Stallman</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    <dc:publisher>No publisher</dc:publisher>
    <dc:creator></dc:creator>
    <dc:rights></dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2013-12-11T22:24:05Z</dc:date>
    <dc:type>News Item</dc:type>
  </item>



</rdf:RDF>
